<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>To the high and honourable House of Peers now in Parliament assembled. The humble petition of John Levet Doctor of Laws, and Mary his wife</title>
            <author>Levet, John, LL.D.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 167KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 26 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B25932</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99829726</idno>
  <idno type="VID">207188</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240861132</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing L1822B</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99829726</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99829726e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B25932)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 207188)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2009:01)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>To the high and honourable House of Peers now in Parliament assembled. The humble petition of John Levet Doctor of Laws, and Mary his wife</title>
                  <author>Levet, John, LL.D.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 24 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1645?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Caption title on pg. 1: The forgery of Mr. Francis Nevile's lease proved.</note>
                  <note>Copy mounted.</note>
                  <note>Imperfect: cropped on right side and at head with loss of text.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original at the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Land titles --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Forgery of manuscripts --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-05 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-01 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-01 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="petition">
            <pb facs="tcp:207188:1"/>
            <head>To the High and Honourable HOUSE of PEERS now in PARLIAMENT Assembled. <hi>The Humble Petition of</hi> John Levet <hi>Doctor of Laws, and</hi> Mary <hi>his Wife.</hi>
            </head>
            <opener>SHEVVETH,</opener>
            <p>THat <hi>Godfrey Copley</hi> Esq; being owner of divers Mannors and Lands in the Counties of <hi>York</hi> and <hi>Notting<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> and he desiring much to prefer your Petitioner <hi>Mary</hi> his near Kinswoman, did upon his Death bed in <hi>Novembe<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> Ninth of King <hi>Charles</hi> the First, make to her several Leases, and other Estates of Lands of good value<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> within seven dayes after dyed.</p>
            <p>That <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> of <hi>Cheet</hi> in the County of <hi>York</hi> Esq; and <hi>William Clayton</hi> Gent. to defeat your Petitioners, caus<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> antedated Lease of some of the same Lands after the Death of the said <hi>G. Copley,</hi> as made to him the said <hi>Francis N<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> to be forged, and attested by six several names of witnesses forged; and procured by bribes, tamperings, and leading Inter<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>tories, <hi>Hugh Everard, John Swinden, James Moseley,</hi> and <hi>Robert Soreby,</hi> four of those six persons whose names<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> set to the said forged Lease as witnesses, to be either wilfully forsworn or deluded by the Conveyance and Release of I<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> in <hi>Fenton</hi> and their Counterparts, and by a Conveyance of <hi>Newmillerdam</hi> and its Counterpart; and by a Deed of <hi>Go<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> Copley</hi>'s Lands, out of which the Lady <hi>Portington</hi> had a Rent Charge af <hi>70. l. per Annum;</hi> and by two other I<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> of Grant, the one of the Parsonage of <hi>Sprotbrough,</hi> and the other of the Parsonage of <hi>Plumtree</hi> then pretended<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> made by <hi>Godfrey Copley</hi> to the said <hi>Francis Nevile,</hi> which are all specified in his own Interrogatories, Letters, and<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> proofs in the books, and whereunto, or to some of them, they had in the life time of the said <hi>G. Copley</hi> subscribed<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> names as witnesses.</p>
            <p>That to countenance this forgery, and other abuses tending thereunto, the said <hi>Francis Nevile,</hi> by the unlawful he<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <hi>John Batt</hi> Esq; then Escheator, and by bribing of <hi>John Goodhand</hi> Esq; then Feodary of the West Riding of the<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> Count of <hi>York,</hi> and by the said <hi>Nevile</hi>'s embracing and bribing of <hi>William Jenkinson</hi> and others of a Jury impan<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> by the said Escheator (the Jury summoned and returned by the Sheriff, of the said County of <hi>York,</hi> then appearin<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> rejected by the said Escheator) corruptly caused an Inquisition after the Death of the said <hi>Godfrey Copley</hi> to be ta<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> wherein the said forg<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>d Lease was found, and after forged, and unduly returned that Office also.</p>
            <p>That then the Defendant <hi>Nevile,</hi> colourably grounded a Suit in the Court of Wards, against the Defendants <hi>Wil<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> Copley,</hi> and <hi>Edmund Hastings,</hi> and <hi>Mary</hi> his Wife, and having there produced the Defendant <hi>William Hawet,</hi>
               <gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> other perjured witnesses, and upon a preagreement, combination, and collusion, with the said <hi>Copley</hi> and <hi>Hastings</hi> (knowing the said Lease to be forged) and by other unlawful means obtained a Decree in that Court, in a Suit wherein<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> Petitioner <hi>Mary</hi> was no party (though principally concerned) for allowance and further countenancing the said fo<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> Lease.</p>
            <p>For which Forgeries, and for the said Defendants <hi>Nevile</hi> and <hi>Clayton</hi> their publishing of that forged Deed, which<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> knew to be forged, and for the said Misdemeanors, your Petitioners commenced a Suit in the <hi>Star Chamber,</hi> where di<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> Witnesses were examined, and the forgeries and Offences fully proved; but by reason of the said <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s tam<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ing with, by himself and others, and by deluding, threatning, bribing, and corrupting some of the Defendants,<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> several witnesses in the Cause; and by reason of many wilfull perjuries committed by the said <hi>Nevile, Clayton,</hi> and s<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> others of the said Defendants, and by the perjuries of <hi>John Pollard, John Holdsworth, William Farburne, Rol<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> Syddall,</hi> and other witnesses; And by reason of the said <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s corrupting of <hi>James Gerrard,</hi> and <hi>Edw<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> Coulson,</hi> Examiners of the Star Chamber. <hi>1.</hi> To examine Witnesses unequally, and to falsifie depositions. <hi>2.</hi> To end<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> and disendorse witnesses names as examined upon the said Lease. <hi>3.</hi> To deliver to the said <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> Depositions ou<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> Court before publication. <hi>4.</hi> To deliver the said <hi>Nevile</hi> the said Lease out of Court without order, that he might tamper u<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> witnesses before he examined them; and by several Orders of that Court, whereby <hi>1.</hi> Some of your Petitioners principal Pr<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> were struck off by a reference and a report upon it. <hi>2.</hi> The Charge of the bill was ordered to be given in one day, by which me<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> some of the Petitioners charges were not touch'd at all, and the other but half opened. <hi>3.</hi> But two witnesses were suffe<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> to be read at the hearing to one point, so as the said <hi>Nevile</hi> having produced three false witnesses, and your Petition<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> twelve honest witnesses to a point (as in truth was done) the said <hi>Nevile</hi>'s three false witnesses were equivalent to<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> Petitioners twelve honest witnesses. <hi>4.</hi> The Examiners foul miscarriages (though fully proved) were not suffered to be<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> at the hearing. <hi>5.</hi> The Court would not grant your Petitioners leave at the hearing to make use of the said Defenda<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> Answers made in other Courts about the said Lease. <hi>6.</hi> That witnesses Depositions in other Courts were allowed to be r<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> for the Defendants, but were not allowed to be read for the Petitioners; some of which Orders were never entred; yet t<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> Court at the hearing held your Petitioners strictly to them; by which means Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi>'s said Lease was justified<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> confirmed by the major part of the Votes of the Court, and your Petitioners Cause destroyed, and their Bill dismissed u<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> great Costs, which they paid to the said Mr. <hi>Nevile.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Now for that the said Forgeries are apparently proved in the said Court of <hi>Star Chamber,</hi> and your Petitioners are<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> to prove all the other exorbitant practises, and misdemeanors of the said <hi>Francis Nevile,</hi> and his Confederates, which<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> such, and so many, as have seldome been heard of in one cause, whereby a provision of <hi>800. l. per Annum,</hi> was ta<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb facs="tcp:207188:2"/> and hath been kept from your Petitioners for above <hi>29</hi> years last past. And for that the said Office, Decree, confirmation <hi>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>cis Nevile</hi>'s said Lease, and dismission of the Petitioners bill (all most unduly obtained) lying in your Petitioners way, <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> never hope for redresse in any ordinary Court of Justice, but meerly by an open and full hearing and knowledge of <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>se in this High Court.</p>
            <p>Your Petitioners most humble Suit therefore is, That this most Honourable House would be pleased to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hear this Cause upon the Proofs of the Books taken in the Star Chamber, and of the Orders there made con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning it, and to suffer your Petitioners at the hearing to make use of all the Defendants Answers and Depo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sitions, and likewise the Depositions of Witnesses which have been made or taken in other Courts concerning the said Lease. And that the said <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> may produce at the hearing his said Lease in question. And to give Order that the said Conveyance and Release of the Lands in <hi>Fenton,</hi> and the said Conveyance of <hi>Newmillerdam</hi> be then likewise produced by those whom they concern, or that have them in their custody. And that <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> produce at the hearing for discovery of the truth, his Counterparts of the said con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veyances of <hi>Newmillerdam</hi> and of the lands in <hi>Fenton,</hi> and also of the Release of the said Lands in <hi>Fenton,</hi> and likewise his Deeds of the Reversion of the Lands of the Lady <hi>Portingtons</hi> said Rent Charge, and of the Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sonages of <hi>Sprotbrough</hi> and of <hi>Plumtree,</hi> which he pretends that <hi>Godfrey Copley</hi> had made unto him. And your Petitioners further pray, That if it may stand with Your Lordships good pleasure (as it did with the House of Commons, in their Appeal to them 29. <hi>Jan.</hi> 1640.) that they may produce at the hearing such Witnesses and Writings as can further manifest the forgery of the said Lease, and the Perjuries of the said Defendants and Witnesses; And likewise the Defendant <hi>Nevile</hi>'s tamperings, subornations, and attempts to suborn, and bribe the Defendants, Witnesses, Examiners, and others. And that upon a full hearing, such damages and reparations may be given to your Petitioners, and such punishment inflicted upon the Delin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quents, as the Justice and merits of the Cause shall require.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>
                  <hi>And your Petitioners shall daily pray,</hi> &amp;c.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div n="1" type="chapter">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:207188:3"/>
            <head>
               <hi>CHAP. I.</hi> The Forgery of Mr. <hi>Francis Nevile's</hi> Lease proved.</head>
            <div n="1" type="section">
               <head>
                  <hi>§. 1.</hi> Mr. <hi>Godfrey Copley</hi>'<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Honesty.</head>
               <p>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">M</seg>R. <hi>Godfrey Copley</hi> was a very honest just dealing man, peaceable, charitable,<note place="margin">
                     <hi>Tho. Vincent</hi> A. 1. Int. 6. <hi>Leonard Wray</hi> A. 143. Int. 6. <hi>Sam. Bower</hi> A. 172. Int. 6. <hi>Ellen Nevile</hi> C. 1. Int. 2.</note> kind to his Kindred and Tenants, and of good Abilities in his understanding.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="2" type="section">
               <head>
                  <hi>§. 2.</hi> Mr. <hi>G. Copley</hi> (being <hi>compos mentis</hi>) made the Petitioners two Leases six or seven dayes before his death.</head>
               <div n="2" type="part">
                  <head>
                     <hi>1.</hi> Mr. <hi>Godfrey Copley</hi> upon the <hi>12.</hi> &amp; <hi>13.</hi> of <hi>November 1633.</hi> made the Petitioner <hi>Mary</hi> two Leases, the one of his Purchased Lands, the other of the Mannor of <hi>Plumtree,</hi> and of all his other Lands in the County of <hi>Nottingham,</hi> and dyed the <hi>19</hi> day of the same Month of <hi>November.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>The one Moyety of the said Leases is made to the Petitioner absolutely,<note place="margin">Petitioners Leases of <hi>12.</hi> &amp; <hi>13.</hi> Nov. <hi>1633.</hi>
                     </note> the other Moyety of them is made to Mrs. <hi>Mary Hastings</hi> in case she and her husband (the Defendant <hi>Hastings</hi>) doe settle the Reversion of the Lordship of <hi>Bentley,</hi> in the County of <hi>York,</hi> (which the said <hi>G. Copley</hi> had formerly purchased in the name of the said <hi>Mary Hastings</hi>) upon the Petitioner <hi>Mary</hi> within one year, next af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter the said <hi>Godfrey Copley</hi>'s Death: But in case they do not so settle <hi>Bentley</hi> upon the said Petitioner <hi>Mary,</hi> then the other Moyety also is by him the said <hi>G. Copley,</hi> setled upon the Petitioner <hi>Mary</hi> for 99. years, in case the Petitioner <hi>Mary,</hi> and the said <hi>Mary Hastings,</hi> and one Mr. <hi>John Copley</hi> of <hi>Doncaster</hi> or any of them should so long live.</p>
                  <p>Mrs. <hi>Hastings</hi> and her husband did not settle <hi>Bentley</hi> upon the Petitioner <hi>Mary,</hi>
                     <note place="margin">Edm. Hastings Fine Pasch. <hi>11</hi> Car. <hi>1.</hi> Reg.</note> but passed it away by Fine to Sir <hi>John Baile</hi> and Mr. <hi>Jobson,</hi> so that thereby both the said Leases are solely the Petitioners.</p>
               </div>
               <div n="2" type="part">
                  <head>
                     <hi>2.</hi> Mr. <hi>Godfrey Copley</hi> made the Pititioners Leases upon his death bed, with these careful, pious, and affectionate expressions, <hi>viz.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p n="1">1. He read and shewed his Deed of power to make them to <hi>Henry Shaw,</hi> who questioned it, and was angry with him for it, and said he would not do what he had not power to do, or what should be questi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>oned after his death.</p>
                  <p n="2">2. He then shewed his affection to be very much to the Petitioner,<note place="margin">
                        <hi>Hen. Shaw</hi> A. 194. Int. 4. 5. 153. 159. 160. 161. 162. 163. 164. 166.</note> and was well pleased that he had done so to her, and hoped that they would be a preferment to her, and that God would blesse her well.</p>
                  <p n="3">3. He said let them that will find fault with me turn the Buckles of their Girdles behind them, for he had made it too sure to her for the hurting her.</p>
                  <p n="4">4. He said to the Petitioner, God blesse thee,<note place="margin">
                        <hi>Godfrey Winter E.</hi> 17. Int. 4. 152. 165.</note> I fear they (her Uncle and Aunt <hi>Hastings</hi>) will wrong thee of that means which I have left thee, and raise their fortunes out of thee. But serve God, and one way or other he will right thee.</p>
                  <p n="5">5.<note place="margin">
                        <hi>Rob. Lund</hi> A. 127. Int. 4. 159. 162. <hi>Tho. Burley</hi> A. 157. Int. 159.</note> He found fault with a Clause in the said Leases (to the Issue of the body of the said <hi>Mary Hastings</hi>) but the Company then present telling him, how <hi>Mary Hastings</hi> was old and not likely to have any Children, and it would be no prejudice to the Petitioner <hi>Mary,</hi> he ceased to move it any further.</p>
                  <p n="6">6. He charged Mrs. <hi>Hastings</hi> to settle <hi>Bentley</hi> upon her the Petitioner, which she protested and vowed to do; and he said, If <hi>Bentley</hi> be not settled upon her, that then <hi>Plumtree,</hi>
                     <note place="margin">
                        <hi>Geo. Holmes</hi> A. 116. Int. 4. 159. 163.</note> and all his Lands in <hi>Nottinghamshire</hi> was too little for her. And if he lived to see her married to his mind, he would make her a better Match.</p>
                  <p n="7">7. He caused Counter-parts to be made thereof, and given to Mr. <hi>Bower</hi> Pa<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>on of the Parish,<note place="margin">
                        <hi>Rich. Elton</hi> A. 146. Int. 152. 154. 164. 166.</note> and hoped <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>hat they would be a means to her from being cheated of her right therein.</p>
                  <p n="8">8. He made the Petitioners Leases freely and of his own accord, and said, She is a good Wench and my near Kinswoman, one that feareth God, and therefore I will make her Leases.<note place="margin">
                        <hi>John Copley</hi> A. 92. Int. 161.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p n="9">9. He said to Mrs. <hi>Hastings,</hi> Use a good Conscience, and deal well and faithfully with <hi>Mal Mote</hi>
                     <pb n="2" facs="tcp:207188:4"/> (the Petitioner) for I have referred her wholly to your care, and if you fail therein, you must answer it before God Almighty. And he desired Mrs. <hi>Nevil</hi> that there might be no suits amongst them about his Estate, for he had left them all enough.</p>
                  <p n="10">
                     <note place="margin">
                        <hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>n. Bower</hi> 172. <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>t. 159.</note>10. He said when he had made the Petitioners Leases, I have now settled all things in peace, and I thank God, though I be weak in body, yet I am now of as good and perfect understanding and memory as ever I was in all my life.</p>
                  <p n="11">
                     <note place="margin">
                        <hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>len Nevil</hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap> 1. Int. 4. 5.</note>11. He much affected the Petitioner a good while before his Death, and seriously wished her prefer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, and at his Death wished Mrs. <hi>Hastings</hi> to do her right, who protested and vowed to settle <hi>Bentley</hi> upon her; and <hi>G. Copley</hi> shewed himself much desirous that the Petitioner might enjoy what he had left her.</p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div n="3" type="section">
               <head>
                  <hi>§. 3. Francis Nevil</hi>'s Oaths and acknowlegments that <hi>G. Copley</hi> had not left him any thing.</head>
               <p n="1">
                  <note place="margin">
                     <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>iz. Rogers</hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> 3. Int. 1.</note>1. In the Countrey about a fortnight before <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s death, his Aunt <hi>Rogers</hi> saying to him, that he was unwise to leave <hi>G. Copley</hi> so near his death, unless he knew how he had dealt with him; <hi>Fran. Nevil</hi> replyed with an Oath, that the said Mr. <hi>Copley</hi> had not given him any thing, but he hoped he would do well for him.</p>
               <p n="2">2. At <hi>London,</hi> upon the first news of Mr. <hi>Godfrey</hi>'s death to Mr. <hi>Godfrey Copley</hi> of <hi>Lincolns</hi>-Inn a Bencher, and to the Lord <hi>Savile.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>First, To Mr. <hi>G. Copley, Francis Nevil</hi> said, <hi>Godfrey Copley</hi> is dead, and hath neither left you nor me any thing,<note place="margin">
                     <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap>. <hi>Copley</hi> A. 66 <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>t. 98.</note> but had given his whole Estate to <hi>William Copley</hi> the Petitioner and others. But <hi>Francis Nevil</hi> said unto him, I will goe into the Countrey, and I will tell them that how they have wrought upon the old Man in his weaknesse, I do not know, but I have fair Deeds made unto me by the said <hi>Godfrey Copley,</hi> when he was in his perfect Memory, and I will Scare them, but I have no more to shew then thou hast; and bound it with an Oath or two: And spake words of disparagement of the defect of the said <hi>William Copley,</hi> to manage so great an Estate as was then left him by the said <hi>G. Copley.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Secondly, To the Lord <hi>Savile,</hi> (saying to him there was a good Wind-fal to you by the death of <hi>Godfrey Copley) Francis Nevil</hi> replyed,<note place="margin">
                     <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                     <hi>Savile B.</hi> 17. <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>nt. 1.</note> Nay, God, they say he hath left me nothing, but if I get down into the Countrey, I shall shuffle amongst them for something.</p>
               <p n="3">3. At his return from <hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ondon</hi> into the Countrey, after <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Death, <hi>Francis Nevil</hi> told Mr.<note place="margin">
                     <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>ionis Cow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>ng</hi> A. 107. <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>nt. 98.</note>
                  <hi>Cowling</hi> at <hi>Doncaster,</hi> (asking him what Mr. <hi>G. Copley</hi> had given him) that he should have it all for Four pence: And then said that the Defendants <hi>Copley</hi> and <hi>Hastings,</hi> went away with the said <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Estate.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="4" type="section">
               <head>
                  <hi>§. 4. Francis Nevil</hi>'s Award betwixt the Defendants <hi>William Copley</hi> and <hi>Edmund Hastings</hi> at difference about the Petitioners Leases.</head>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>dm. Hastings <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>xam.</hi> 53. <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>nt. 12. <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>dm. Hastings</hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> 67. Int. 12. <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>arth. Roulston</hi> A. 160. Int. 71. <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>3. <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>ervas Eyr</hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>. 86. Int. 1, <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>, 3.</note>
                  <hi>Francis Nevil,</hi> after <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Death, offered himself to make an Award betwixt the Defendants <hi>William Copley</hi> and <hi>Edmund Hastings</hi> then at difference about the Petitioners Leases, and by his strong<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly suggesting to <hi>Edmund Hastings</hi> that <hi>G. Copley</hi> had not power to make them, caused Mr. <hi>Hastings</hi> to waive her Leases, and to accept of a Lease of the Demeasne of <hi>Plumtree</hi> for 21. years paying 2 <hi>d.</hi> Rent from the Defendant <hi>Copley,</hi> and to give him 1400 <hi>l.</hi> for it, and bound them in 10000 <hi>l.</hi> Bonds apiece to stand to that Award; and <hi>Francis Nevil</hi> then expressed that <hi>G. Copley</hi> had left him nothing at all</p>
            </div>
            <div n="5" type="section">
               <head>
                  <hi>§. 5. Francis Nevil</hi>'s Letter to the Lady <hi>Portington</hi> expressing the said Award and to whom <hi>G. Copley</hi> had left his Estate, and what he had left him.</head>
               <q>
                  <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                     <body>
                        <div type="letter">
                           <opener>
                              <salute>MAdam,</salute>
                           </opener>
                           <p>
                              <note place="margin">
                                 <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                                    <desc>•</desc>
                                 </gap>ran. Nevils Letter Dec. <hi>18.</hi>
                              </note> My duty remembred; In my return from <hi>London,</hi> my purpose was to have seen you, but partly fearing your not being at home, and partly drawn on with my Company, I took up my lodg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing at <hi>Sprotborough,</hi> where I mist the best Friend that ever man had; and instead of him, <hi>found diffe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rences betwixt all those to whom he left his Estate;</hi> and most implacable and unnatural ones, betwixt the Brother and Sister; My ever honoured Kinsman buried (as I heard) if with Christian, yet I dare say not with decent buriall: I laboured to reconcile these swelling and blustering discords of my kinred, but being a Task too great for me, and a businesse that hung of so many strings, I desired them to nominate Friends, time and place for that purpose, which they did; so <hi>Anthony Eyr</hi> of <hi>Rampton, Gervase Eyr</hi> a <hi>Lei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cestershire</hi> man, Mr. <hi>John Copley,</hi> and my Self, were appointed: We met at <hi>Sprotborough,</hi> and after three dayes debate, ended the business as followeth; <hi>William Copley</hi> is to make a Lease of <hi>Plumtree</hi> De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mesnes, to Mr. <hi>Hastings</hi> and his Wife for <hi>21</hi> years, if they live so long, paying two pence rent; <hi>Will. Copley</hi> is to release to Mr. <hi>Hastings</hi> and his Wife, all his Interest in the Mannor of <hi>Bentley. Will. Copley</hi> is to have all the goods at <hi>Sprotborough,</hi> save a little old Corn, and some little Houshold-stuffe, all not worth above <hi>150 l.</hi> and the Stock there was valued to <hi>1400 l.</hi> Mr. <hi>Hastings</hi> and his Wife are to have all <hi>Plumtree</hi> Stoc.k, Mr. <hi>Hastings</hi> and his Wife have <hi>500 l.</hi> upon a Mortgage made to my Cousin <hi>God<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>frey</hi>
                              <pb n="3" facs="tcp:207188:5"/> by Mr. <hi>Wray,</hi> and a Mortgage of <hi>William Copleys</hi> of <hi>Wadworth,</hi>
                              <note place="margin">
                                 <hi>Rob. Heywar<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                       <desc>•…</desc>
                                    </gap>
                                 </hi> Jurat. <hi>Isabel Rogers</hi> A. 110. Int. 105. <hi>Eliz. Rogers</hi> B. 3. Int. 13. <hi>Anthony Gilby</hi> B. 14. Int. 13.</note> and to have <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                                 <desc>•</desc>
                              </gap>o other benefit of their Executorship, save a aforesaid. My Mother goes away with the money, Bils and Bonds. And thus you see a good mans estate miserably anat omized, whose funerals, if he have any, must be discharged by them both equally, I mean the Brother and Sister. I gave the Tenants that are your security for your <hi>70 l.</hi> by year, warning to pay their rent to none but you, <hi>the Reversion of which Lands my Cousin hath given to me.</hi> I shall in the latter end of <hi>Christmas,</hi> send you my Rent; and in the mean time, rest.</p>
                           <closer>
                              <dateline>Cheet <date>
                                    <hi>this 18.</hi> December Concord. cum Origin.</date>
                              </dateline>
                              <signed>Your dutiful Nephew <hi>FRANCIS NEVILE.</hi>
                              </signed>
                           </closer>
                           <postscript>
                              <p>Note, Francis Nevile <hi>acknowledgeth in this his Letter Mr.</hi> G. Copley <hi>to be a good man (thus you see a good mans Estate miserably anatomized) for Mr.</hi> G. Copley <hi>a good man to make the Petitioners Leases upon his death bed, and to have made</hi> Francis Nevil <hi>a Lease of the same Lands a year before, is</hi> contradictio in adjecto, <hi>a meer contradiction.</hi>
                              </p>
                           </postscript>
                        </div>
                     </body>
                  </floatingText>
               </q>
            </div>
            <div n="6" type="section">
               <head>
                  <hi>§. 6 Francis Nevile</hi> said to the Lady <hi>Portington,</hi> that as God should judge his Soul, he had nothing to do with <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s <hi>Nottinghamshire</hi> Lands, but he had Leases of his <hi>Yorkshire</hi> Lands.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> soon after the said Letter, swore to the Lady <hi>Portington,</hi> asking him who went <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ay with <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s <hi>Nottinghamshire</hi> Lands, that as God should judge his soul,<note place="margin">
                     <hi>Isabell Rogers</hi> A. 110. Int. 101 114. <hi>Eliz. Rogers</hi> B. 3. Int. 2.</note> he had nothing to do with any of them, but he had Leases of <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s <hi>York-shire</hi> Lands, and before Supper he said they were witnessed only with Three Witnesses, and after Supper he said they had six Witnesses to them, to which the Lady <hi>Portington</hi> replied, Nephew hath my Table added Three Witnesses to them? burn them for you will have no credit by them.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="7" type="section">
               <head>
                  <hi>§. 7. Francis Nevile</hi> after all these Oaths, Letter, and Actions, produc'd his forged Lease of <hi>Plumtree</hi> and of <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s other <hi>Nottinghamshire</hi> Lands, attested with six wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nesses Names forged, as will thus appear.</head>
               <div n="1" type="part">
                  <p n="1">1. <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> shewed it to Sir <hi>John Waidson</hi> after <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Death, for to reconcile him and the Defendant <hi>Copley</hi> about it, with the Names of <hi>Thomas Walker</hi> and <hi>Richard Elton</hi> only endorsed upon it as witnesses, and afterwards he shewed it to him again with the other four added to it. And Sir <hi>John Waidson</hi> then told him that his witnesses were well multiplied since he first saw it.</p>
                  <p>He saith that <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> shewed his said Lease to him at his house in <hi>Cheet</hi> about the 14. 15. or 16. of <hi>December,</hi> next after <hi>G. Copleys</hi> Death,<note place="margin">Sr. <hi>Ioh. Waidson</hi> B. 20. Int. 1.</note> and told him that he was the first that ever saw it by his shewing, and said then that it was given him by his Mother, and that he had had it in his hands about 5 or 6 dayes, and then there were only two witnesses subscribed and endorsed upon it <hi>(viz.) Thomas Walker</hi> and <hi>Richard Elton;</hi> and <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> told him the reason why there were no more witnesses to it, was, for that his Mother and <hi>Mary Hastings</hi> endevoured to get what they could one from the other, and took their Opportunities at such secret times, as they could best perfect their businesse, and therefore <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> told him that they could have no more witnesses unto it.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> betwixt St.<note place="margin">Int. 2.</note>
                     <hi>Stephens</hi> and <hi>New Years</hi> day following shewed him the said Lease<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> again at <hi>Cheet</hi> aforesaid. At which time there was an increase of Four witnesses names unto it, and then he told <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> that the witnesses were well multiplied since he last saw it.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> when he first shewed him the said Lease, he also shewed him two or three other Lea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ses with the same two Witnesses unto them, <hi>viz. Thomas Walker,</hi> and <hi>Richard Elton</hi> only,<note place="margin">Int. 7.</note> the one of certain Lands in <hi>Sprotbrough</hi> and other Lands, and the other of the <hi>Advowson</hi> of <hi>Plumtree,</hi> as made by the said <hi>G. Copley.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>At the second time at <hi>Cheet</hi> aforesaid, when he saw the increase of the Witnesses to the Lease now in question, he saw an increase of the same Witnesses to the other Leases likewise,<note place="margin">Int. 8.</note> and they were all shewed unto him by the said <hi>Francis Nevill.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> shewed him the aforesaid Leases,<note place="margin">Int. 9.</note> and desired him to deliver this Message to the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendant <hi>William Copley (viz.)</hi> That he would give him all his right he had by any Act of <hi>G. Copley</hi> of his Lands in <hi>York-shire,</hi> and the Inheritance of <hi>Bentley,</hi> which <hi>G. Copley</hi> had lately given to <hi>Mary Hastings</hi> and <hi>Mary Mote,</hi> for his the said <hi>William Copleys</hi> Inheritance in <hi>Plumtree</hi> and his other <hi>Not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinghamshire</hi> Lands which are worth 20000 <hi>l.</hi> And if he could not recover <hi>Bentley</hi> by Law, he would purchase it for him, or else secure him as valuable Lands of his own both for Possession and Reversion. And he would content Mr. <hi>Hastings</hi> for his Interest, and give the Petitioner <hi>Mary</hi> 2000 <hi>l.</hi> to her Marriage, and this Message he conceiveth was the only reason why <hi>Francis Nevill</hi> shewed him his said Leases.</p>
                  <div type="subsection">
                     <head>Sir <hi>John Waidson</hi> ex parte <hi>Francis Nevile.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <p>He saith; this is the same Lease that <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> shewed him with six Witnesses at <hi>Christmas</hi> 1633.<note place="margin">Sr. <hi>Ioh. Waidson ex parte</hi> Defr. G. 1. Int. 9.</note> and with but two witnesses at the time when <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> first shewed it to him, for that it containeth the same matter, for that the said <hi>Walker</hi> and <hi>Elton</hi> are Witnesses to it, and the other four Witnesses are
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:207188:6"/> the same that he saw to it at <hi>Christmas</hi> 1633. And he did see the same Lease when he was examined to it as Witnesse on <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s part at <hi>Barnesly,</hi> betwixt him and Mr. <hi>Hastings,</hi> to Testifie that he had se<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> it before, he delivered the Messuage from <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> to Mr. <hi>Copley</hi> and Mr. <hi>Hastings.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <note place="margin">
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>t. 10.</note>He acquainted both before and after <hi>Christmas</hi> 1633. the said Defendants, <hi>Copley</hi> and <hi>Hastings,</hi> with the said <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s Leases, and he informed Mr. <hi>Hastings</hi> with the Lease of <hi>Plumtree</hi> in particular, and as he believes he deposed to the same effect at <hi>Barnesley</hi> in <hi>April</hi> 1635.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="subsection">
                     <head>Sir <hi>John Waidson</hi> is confirmed by these <hi>4.</hi> circumstances.</head>
                     <p n="1">
                        <note place="margin">
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>r. <hi>Joh. Waidson</hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>. 16. Int. 9 <hi>
                              <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                 <desc>•…</desc>
                              </gap>ead the</hi> Interr. <hi>
                              <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                 <desc>•…</desc>
                              </gap>ob. Conyers</hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap> 38. Int. 2. 3.</note>1. By <hi>Fr. Nevile</hi>'s interrogating of him, if the Parsonages of <hi>Sprotbrough</hi> and <hi>Plumtree</hi> were not the two writings he at first time shewed to him, being Witnessed only with two Witnesses.</p>
                     <p n="2">2. By <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s confession to Mr. <hi>Conyers</hi> that he did shew his Lease now in question, to Sir <hi>John Waidson</hi> twice before, and in <hi>Christmas</hi> Hollydayes 1633. at his House in <hi>Cheet,</hi> and for the same reason that Sir <hi>John Waidson</hi> deposeth, <hi>viz.</hi> about reconciling some differences between him the said <hi>Fran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cis Nevile</hi> and the Defendant <hi>William Copley.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p n="3">
                        <note place="margin">
                           <hi>
                              <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                 <desc>•…</desc>
                              </gap>rancis Justice</hi> 3. 33. Int. 2, <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>, 4.</note>3. By Sir <hi>John Waidson</hi>'s intimating of it to his Servant <hi>Francis Justice</hi> at their first return from <hi>Cheet</hi> before <hi>Christmas</hi> 1633. Sir <hi>John</hi> said, that Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi> would have a good share in <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s estate. And at their second return from <hi>Cheete</hi> in the said <hi>Christmas</hi> Sir <hi>John</hi> holding up his hands, said that Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi> had shewed him such writings that almost amazed him.</p>
                     <p n="4">
                        <note place="margin">
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>ir <hi>John Waid<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                              <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                 <desc>•…</desc>
                              </gap>on</hi> G. 1. Int. 7. 12. <hi>
                              <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                 <desc>•…</desc>
                              </gap>x parte Def. Darcy Washin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                              <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                 <desc>•…</desc>
                              </gap>on</hi> B. 55. Int. 1 <hi>Tho. Lewis</hi> B. 43. Int. 4.</note>4▪ By Sir <hi>John Waidson</hi>'s revealing of it to Sir <hi>John Jackson</hi> immediatly after he had seen it the second tim<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> and shortly after to the Defendant <hi>Copley,</hi> to Mr. <hi>Washington,</hi> and to Mr. <hi>Lewis,</hi> two years before the Petitioners intermarriage, and that because <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> used the Defendant <hi>Copley</hi> very unconscionably.</p>
                  </div>
               </div>
               <div n="2" type="part">
                  <p n="2">2. Tho. Walker (<hi>the first of the two Witnesses Sir</hi> John Waidson <hi>had onely seen endorsed upon it) denyes his name upon it to be of his own hand Writing, and</hi> G. Copley<hi>'s sealing and delivering of it.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <note place="margin">
                        <hi>Tho. Walker</hi> B. 75. Int. 6. <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap> 10.</note>He saith that he neither knows nor believes that <hi>G. Copley</hi> did seal and deliver <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s said Lease, neither is his Name to it of his own hand writing, and he knows it to be true, for that there are some letters in it, that he never makes in such a forme, nor is it sealed with <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Seal of Armes with which he usually sealed, when he sealed any writings.</p>
               </div>
               <div n="3" type="part">
                  <p n="3">3. Richard Elton <hi>(the other Witnesse) which Sir</hi> John Waidson <hi>had only seen, together with</hi> Tho. Walker <hi>at the Lease after</hi> G. Copley<hi>'s death, denyes his Name to be of his Hand-writing, and</hi> G. Copley<hi>'s sealing and delivering of it.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <note place="margin">
                        <hi>Rich. Elton</hi> A. 146. Int. 32.</note>He saith that the Impression of the Seal to <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s said Lease, is not like <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Seal, so far as he can judge thereof; an<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> he believeth that the Name of <hi>Rich. Elton</hi> endorsed on it, is not of his own hand-writing, for that he doth not use to make such Letters as some of those are, nor can he write so good a hand; and he knows not of the sealing and delivering of it, nor ever heard it read, or saw it delivered.</p>
               </div>
               <div n="4" type="part">
                  <p n="4">
                     <note place="margin">Interrogate this.</note>4. <hi>Interrogate.</hi> If <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> shewed not his said Lease to another witnesse without all excepti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons after <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s death, with the Names of <hi>Thomas Walker</hi> and <hi>Richard Elton</hi> endorsed on it as Witnesses, who then told <hi>Francis Nevile,</hi> that <hi>Richard Elton</hi>'s Name to it was no whit like his own hand-writing, for <hi>Elton</hi> could not write half so well; and before <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Office was found, <hi>Francis Ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vile</hi> shewed him his said Lease again, and he then told the said <hi>Francis Nevile,</hi> that he had well amen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded <hi>Richard Elton</hi>'s name to it, and made it far more like his Hand-writing, than it was, when he shewed to him before, onely he had mistaken in one or two letters in it, for which he thought <hi>Richard Elton</hi> would not justify it to be of his own Hand-writing.</p>
               </div>
               <div n="5" type="part">
                  <p n="5">5. <hi>The Perjuries or delusions of the other four Witnesses endorsed upon the said Lease, will further ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pear by their own Depositions and contradictions, and by the subsequent proofs.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <div n="1" type="subsection">
                     <head>
                        <hi>1.</hi> Hugh Everard.</head>
                     <p>
                        <note place="margin">
                           <hi>Hugh Everard</hi> A. 13. Int. 8.</note>He, <hi>John Swinden, James Moseley, Robert Soreby,</hi> and he is perswaded, <hi>Tho. Walker</hi> and <hi>Rich. Elton</hi> were Witnesses to some Writings Sealed and delivered by <hi>G. Copley</hi> and <hi>Francis Nevile,</hi> the one to the other severally, about 10. <hi>Decemb.</hi> 8. <hi>Car.</hi> They joyntly sealed and delivered the Assurance of <hi>Fen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ton</hi> to him and <hi>Tho. Denton,</hi> for the use of Mrs. <hi>Cuttler.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <note place="margin">Int. 13.</note>He at the same time, together with the rest of the Witnesses aforesaid, did all subscribe their Names as Witnesses To three Writings Sealed by <hi>G. Copley</hi> to <hi>Francis Nevile.</hi> And to one Sealed by <hi>Francis Nevile,</hi> to <hi>G. Copley.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>He formerly asked <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> whether <hi>G. Copley</hi> would willingly joyn with him in the sale of the Lands in <hi>Fenton;</hi>
                        <note place="margin">Int. 24.</note> whereto he answered, he knew he would, for he would secure him by other lands in lieu thereof. He verily thinketh that <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> did give <hi>G. Copley</hi> security therein out of the Lands and Milnes of <hi>Newmillerdam,</hi> and it may be that thus much he hath declared to several persons. And he doth conceive, and ever hath done, that the Writings which were sealed by the said Mr. <hi>Copley,</hi> and not suffered by him to be read, did not any way concern the Estate of <hi>Newmillerdam.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <pb facs="tcp:207188:7"/>
                     <p>He doth not remember that the said Deed of <hi>Newmillerdame,</hi>
                        <note place="margin">Int. 28.</note> was read over to the Witnesses at the time of the sealing and delivery thereof.</p>
                     <p>He at <hi>Wakefield</hi> at <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Office finding,<note place="margin">
                           <hi>Hugh Evera<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                 <desc>•…</desc>
                              </gap>
                           </hi> K. 8. Int. 20</note> gave evidence of the execution of writings then produ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ced by <hi>Francis Nevile,</hi> and formerly executed by <hi>G. Copley</hi> to <hi>Francis Nevile.</hi> And at <hi>Barnsly</hi> and at <hi>Doncaster,</hi> hath been examined of all or some of the said Writings. <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> never gave or pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mised him in earnest any Reward or Curtesie for testefying as aforesaid, other then one quart of Wine, and the merry offer of the Parsonage of <hi>Plumtree.</hi> The Lease now shewed to him is one of the same Leases. His Name endorsed as a witnesse thereof is of his own hand writing. It was executed in his presence in the life time of <hi>G. Copley</hi> at <hi>Sprotbrough</hi> about 10 <hi>December</hi> 1632. and in the presence of <hi>James Mosely, John Swinden, Robert Soreby</hi> and others.</p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>G. Copley</hi> did about 10. <hi>December</hi> 1632.<note place="margin">
                           <hi>Hugh Everard</hi> A. 13. Int. 3</note> seal and deliver divers Writings as his Acts and Deeds and he doth verily believe that the writing now to him shewed, is one of them, for that his name is by him endorsed on the Backside thereof as a Witnesse. <hi>Thomas Denton</hi> was not present in the Room at the time of the sealing of the said Lease.</p>
                     <p>He saith that his Name endorsed on the Backside of this Writing, now to him shewed,<note place="margin">Int. 33.</note> is of his own hand writing so far as he can judge by the sight thereof.</p>
                     <p>He doth write so plain a hand, as he thinketh it may very well be counterfeited,<note place="margin">Int. 34.</note> and hath been by Mr. <hi>Elmehurst</hi>'s Clark, to a Copy of the Register Book of the Parish of <hi>Wosbrough</hi> sent to <hi>York.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>He saith that he is not certain whether the said <hi>G.</hi>
                        <note place="margin">Int. 19.</note>
                        <hi>Copley</hi> did deliver the said Writings to the said <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> or no, but thinketh that he did.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="subsection">
                     <head>Reply.</head>
                     <p n="1">1. The Interrogatory to the Deposition <hi>K.</hi> 8. <hi>Int.</hi> 20. is leading.<note place="margin">
                           <hi>Hugh Evera<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                 <desc>•…</desc>
                              </gap>
                           </hi> K. 69. Int. 2<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap> read the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terrogatory.</note> Gave you not evidence at <hi>Wakefield</hi> for Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi>'s Leases? Have you not at sundry time since, at <hi>Doncaster</hi> twice, and once at <hi>Barnesly</hi> been examined concerning them.</p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Note,</hi> He formerly deposed for it, mind him of it, and he will do it again.</p>
                     <p n="2">2. The merry offer the Parsonage of <hi>Plumtree</hi> (worth 300. <hi>l.</hi>
                        <note place="margin">K. Int. 20.</note>
                        <hi>per Annum</hi>) is a fair Insinuation (if not a bribe) to animate him to depose for it.</p>
                     <p n="3">3. He knew not the Contents, for <hi>G. Copley</hi> would nor suffer them to be read.<note place="margin">A. Int. 24.</note>
                     </p>
                     <p>How can he then depose absolutely for them?</p>
                     <p n="4">4. His Contradictions or Perjuries.</p>
                     <div n="1" type="item">
                        <head>
                           <hi>1.</hi> In <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s sealing and delivering of the said Lease.</head>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s Lease is one of the said Writings, it was sealed and delivered by <hi>G. Copley.</hi>
                           <note place="margin">K. Int. 2<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                 <desc>•…</desc>
                              </gap>
                           </note>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Contrar.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>He doth verely believe that <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s Lease is one of them.<note place="margin">A. Int. 35.</note>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Note,</hi> The former is absolute, the Latter is limited to his Belief. His Limitation is his legall deposition.</p>
                     </div>
                     <div n="2" type="item">
                        <head>
                           <hi>2.</hi> In the person to whom the said Lease was delivered.</head>
                        <p>
                           <hi>G. Copley</hi> then sealed and delivered three Writings to <hi>Francis Nevile.</hi>
                           <note place="margin">A. Int. 13</note>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>G. Copley</hi> executed them to <hi>Francis Nevile.</hi>
                           <note place="margin">K. Int. 20.</note>
                        </p>
                        <p>Sealed and delivered by <hi>G. Copley &amp; Francis Nevile,</hi> the one to the other severally.<note place="margin">A. Int. 8.</note>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Contrar.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>He is not certain whether the said <hi>G. Copley</hi> did deliver the said Writings to <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> or not,<note place="margin">A. Int. 19.</note> but thinketh that he did.</p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Note.</hi> 1. He is a desperate (if not a perjured) witnesse, to depose certainly to three several Inter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rogatories and yet he is not certain.</p>
                        <p n="2">2. What deposition is thinking that he did, for an Estate of 800. <hi>l. per Annum,</hi> and against such a Cloud of Witnesses, and the Act of an honest Gentleman upon his Death Bed (no time of dissimula<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion) and to the Petitioner his neer Kinswoman, then but 12. or 13. years of Age, and meerly out of his great affection to her, being born, bred, and then living in his house, and not desiring him to do it.</p>
                     </div>
                     <div n="3" type="item">
                        <head>
                           <hi>3.</hi> In the reason of his deposing for it, <hi>viz.</hi> his name to it to be of his own hand writing.</head>
                        <p>He doth verily believe that <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s Lease is one of them,<note place="margin">A. Int. 35.</note> for that his Name is by him en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dorsed on the backside thereof.</p>
                        <p>His name endorsed as a Witness thereof is of his own Hand-Writing.<note place="margin">K. Int. 20.</note>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Contrar.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>His Name endorsed on the backside thereof, is of his owne hand writing,<note place="margin">A. Int. 33.</note> so far as he can judge by the sight thereof.</p>
                        <p>He doth write so plain a hand, that he thinketh it may very well be counterfeited,<note place="margin">A. Int. 34 <hi>Emanuel</hi>
                              <gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                                 <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                              </gap> D. 69. Int.</note> and it hath been by Mr. <hi>Elmhursts</hi> Clerk to a Copy of the Register Book of the Parish of <hi>Wosbrough</hi> sent to <hi>York</hi>
                        </p>
                     </div>
                     <div n="4" type="item">
                        <head>
                           <hi>4.</hi> In <hi>Thomas Walker</hi> and <hi>Richard Elton</hi> their subscribing their names to it as witnesses.</head>
                        <p>He is perswaded that <hi>Thomas Walker</hi> and <hi>Richard Elton</hi> subscribed their names to it as Witnesses.<note place="margin">A. Int. 8.</note>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Contrar.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>He at the same time together with the witnesses aforesaid, did all subscribe their names to it as witnesses.<note place="margin">A. Int. 13</note>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Note,</hi> 1. In the 8. <hi>Interr.</hi> he is but perswaded, in the 13. he is positive that <hi>Walker</hi> and <hi>Elton</hi> sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>scribed their Names to it as witnesses. A perswasion and a positive deposition is one and the same with him. Doth not he make himself a desperate witnesse?</p>
                        <p n="2">2. <hi>Thomas Walker</hi> and <hi>Richard Elton</hi> have denyed that they writ their names upon it, and gave good reasons for it. Do not they make him a perjur'd witnesse?</p>
                     </div>
                     <div n="5" type="item">
                        <head>
                           <hi>5.</hi> In the number of the private writings then sealed and delivered by <hi>G. Copley</hi> and <hi>Francis Nevile,</hi> and what he conceived they did concern, he is contradocted by five able witnesses.</head>
                        <p>He was a witnesse to three Writings then sealed by <hi>G. Copley</hi> to <hi>Francis Nevile,</hi>
                           <note place="margin">A. Int. 1<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                                 <desc>•</desc>
                              </gap>.</note> and to one sealed by <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> to <hi>G. Copley.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <pb facs="tcp:207188:8"/>
                        <p>
                           <note place="margin">
                              <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                                 <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                              </gap>. Int. 24.</note>He doth conceive and ever hath done, that the Writings which were sealed by the said <hi>G. Copley,</hi> and not by him suffered to be read, did not any way concern the estate of <hi>Newmillerdame.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Contrar.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <note place="margin">
                              <hi>
                                 <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                    <desc>•…</desc>
                                 </gap>illiam Birks</hi>
                              <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                 <desc>•…</desc>
                              </gap>. 108. Int. 24. <hi>
                                 <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                    <desc>•…</desc>
                                 </gap>ill. Neschall</hi>
                              <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                 <desc>•…</desc>
                              </gap>. 15. Int. 24. <hi>
                                 <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                    <desc>•…</desc>
                                 </gap>ter Levet.</hi> E. 8. Int. 24. 25. <hi>
                                 <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                    <desc>•…</desc>
                                 </gap>illiam Key</hi>
                              <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                 <desc>•…</desc>
                              </gap>. 67. Int. 1. <hi>
                                 <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                    <desc>•…</desc>
                                 </gap>manuel Mote</hi>
                              <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                                 <desc>•</desc>
                              </gap>ledge. 69. Int. 6. <hi>
                                 <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                    <desc>•…</desc>
                                 </gap>hn Swinden</hi>
                              <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                 <desc>•…</desc>
                              </gap>. 48. Int. 7.</note>
                           <hi>Hugh Everard</hi> acknowledged that there were but 2. or 3. private Writings then sealed and delivered betwixt <hi>G. Copley</hi> and <hi>Francis Nevile.</hi> And that <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> first sealed and <hi>G. Copley</hi> last, and that he did conceive, verily believe, and think in his soul and conscience, that they did only concern <hi>Newmiller<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dame</hi> and its Counterpart, and for that <hi>Fenton</hi> was passed away to him and the Feoffees wherein <hi>G. Copley</hi> was interessed, that <hi>Newmillerdame</hi> was passed to <hi>G. Copley</hi> in lieu and satisfaction thereof.</p>
                     </div>
                  </div>
                  <div n="2" type="subsection">
                     <head>
                        <hi>2. John Swinden</hi> another Witnesse to <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s Lease.</head>
                     <p>He, <hi>Hugh Everard, Thomas Denton, James Mosely,</hi> and <hi>Robert Soreby,</hi> went to the house of <hi>G. Copley</hi> in <hi>Sprotbrough,</hi> about 10. <hi>December</hi> 1632. to take an assurance of <hi>Fenton</hi> for Mrs <hi>Cutler</hi>'s use. And there met with two other Witnesses, which he thinketh were <hi>Thomas Walker</hi> and <hi>Richard Elton. G. Copley</hi> and <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> did then and there jointly and severally seal certain writings to the number of five or six. Whereunto he, and the other persons aforenamed (except Mr. <hi>Everard</hi> to the Conveyance of <hi>Fenton</hi>) did endorse their names as Witnesses. He never met with the said Witnesses, nor ever was at the sealing of any other Writing at the house of the said <hi>G. Copley,</hi> at any other time but at the time aforesaid.</p>
                     <p>
                        <note place="margin">
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>nt. 9.</note>All the said Writings were then immediately sealed one after another. The three Leases sealed by <hi>G. Copley</hi> to <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> vvere first sealed and delivered. <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s Writing to <hi>G. Copley</hi> vvas next sealed and delivered. The Conveyance of <hi>Fenton</hi> vvas last sealed and delivered and vvas read.</p>
                     <p>
                        <note place="margin">
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>nt. 22.</note>The Lands in <hi>Fenton</hi> vvere <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s, and he had the money vvhich vvas paid for them. <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> had made some Estate of them to <hi>G. Copley</hi> to secure him from some engagements, vvhich he had entred into for <hi>Francis Nevile,</hi> and therefore <hi>G. Copley</hi> joyned vvith <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> in the Conveyance of them.</p>
                     <p>
                        <note place="margin">
                           <hi>
                              <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                 <desc>•…</desc>
                              </gap>hn Swinden</hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>. 23. Int. 20.</note>He gave evidence at <hi>Wakefield</hi> at <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Office finding, and twice since for some Leases executed by <hi>Godfrey Copley.</hi> This is one of them. His name unto it is of his ovvn proper hand Writing. It vvas sealed and delivered by <hi>G. Copley</hi> to <hi>Francis Nevile,</hi> in the presence of him, <hi>Hugh Everard, James Moseley, Robert Soreby,</hi> all knovvn to him and others then and there present, vvhom he knevv not, vvho subscribed their names on the Backside thereof. He is persvvaded the persons vvhose names are endorsed thereon, vvhere the same persons unknovvn to him who thereunto endorsed their names. The Assurance of <hi>Fenton</hi> was the occasion of his going thither.</p>
                     <p>
                        <note place="margin">
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>on Swinden <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>urt of Wards <hi>
                              <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                 <desc>•…</desc>
                              </gap>l. 7. Int. 17. <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                 <desc>•…</desc>
                              </gap>ter</hi> Nevile <hi>&amp;</hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>astings.</note>He saith that <hi>G. Copley</hi> delivered a Writing or Writings to <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s use, about <hi>November</hi> vvas 2. years, to vvhich his name is subscribed as a Witnesse, vvhich vvas not published in his hearing though he desired it. And saith that the same Writing or Writings after sealing and delivering thereof, vvere to his best remembrance delivered sealed up in a Box to the Complainant <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s man <hi>William Hawet.</hi> Neither remembreth he vvho vvas present at the sealing and delivering of the said Wri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting or Writings save Mr. <hi>Everard</hi> and himself.</p>
                     <p>
                        <note place="margin">
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                              <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                           </gap>. 48. Int. 37.</note>
                        <hi>G. Copley</hi> then said, Cousin <hi>Nevile,</hi> I deliver this as my Act and Deed. Shortly after the said Wri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tings vvere given in a Boxe, to the said Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi> to his remembrance.</p>
                     <p>
                        <note place="margin">
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>nt. 20.</note>He saith that after he had vvritten his name as a Witnesse to the said Writings, he medled no more vvith them, and remembreth not vvhether they vvere left on the Table or in the Room vvith the said vvritings vvhich concerned the Lands in <hi>Fenton</hi> or no.</p>
                     <p>
                        <note place="margin">
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>nt. 38.</note>He deposed for <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s said Lease, and his tvvo other Leases at <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Office finding, but vvhat Lands vvere comprized vvithin the same, he knows not, for they were never read unto him. And the reason why he did so depose, was for that he did see his name written on the Backside thereof, as a Witness to the same.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="subsection">
                     <head>Reply.</head>
                     <p n="1">1. The <hi>Interrogat.</hi> to K. 23. <hi>Int.</hi> 20. is the same that was to <hi>Hugh Everard,</hi> and is leading.</p>
                     <p n="2">2. The Reason why he deposed for the said Lease, and <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s other two Leases, at <hi>G. Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pley</hi>'s Office finding was, for that he did see his name written on the backside thereof as a Witnesse.</p>
                     <p>He knows not what Lands were in them, for they were never read unto him.</p>
                     <p n="3">3. His Contradictions or Perjuries.</p>
                     <div n="1" type="item">
                        <head>
                           <hi>1.</hi> In the number of Writings then sealed and delivered by <hi>G. Copley.</hi>
                        </head>
                        <p>
                           <note place="margin">A. Int. 9.</note>
                           <hi>G. Copley</hi> delivered three Writings to <hi>Francis Nevile.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Contrar.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <note place="margin">
                              <hi>
                                 <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                    <desc>•…</desc>
                                 </gap>ohn Swinden Court of wards</hi>
                              <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                 <desc>•…</desc>
                              </gap>. Int. 17. <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                 <desc>•…</desc>
                              </gap>. Int. 7.</note>
                           <hi>G. Copley</hi> delivered a writing or writings to <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s use.</p>
                     </div>
                     <div n="2" type="item">
                        <head>
                           <hi>2.</hi> In the number of Witnesses to them.</head>
                        <p>He, <hi>Everard, Thomas Denton, Mosely, Soreby, Walker,</hi> and <hi>Elton,</hi> did endorse their names to them as witnesses.</p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Contrar.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <note place="margin">
                              <hi>
                                 <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                    <desc>•…</desc>
                                 </gap>ourt of Wards</hi>
                              <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                 <desc>•…</desc>
                              </gap>ol. 7. Int. 17 <hi>
                                 <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                    <desc>•…</desc>
                                 </gap>ohn Swinden</hi> A. 48. Int. 35.</note>He remembreth not who were present at the sealing and delivery of the said writing or writings, save Mr. <hi>Everard</hi> and himself.</p>
                        <p>He remembreth not that <hi>Thomas Denton</hi> was in the Room when the writings were so sealed by <hi>G. Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pley</hi> as aforesaid.</p>
                        <p>
                           <note place="margin">
                              <hi>Thomas Denton</hi> E. 6. Int. 7. Vide <hi>Francis Nevils</hi> Lease.</note>
                           <hi>Thomas Denton</hi> did not then see any other writings then what concerned <hi>Fenton</hi> there sealed and deli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vered by the said <hi>G. Copley,</hi> not was any witness to the same, for he went away.</p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Thomas Denton</hi> is not endorsed as a Witnesse upon <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s Lease.</p>
                        <pb facs="tcp:207188:9"/>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Thomas Walker</hi> and <hi>Richard Elton</hi> have denyed their names upon it to be of then <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>n hand writing.<note place="margin">ut supra.</note>
                        </p>
                        <p>Is not this a Perjury?</p>
                     </div>
                     <div n="3" type="item">
                        <head>
                           <hi>3.</hi> In the Person to whom the said Writings were delivered after they were sealed.</head>
                        <p>Shortly after the sealing and delivery thereof, the said Writings were given in a Box to the said Mr.<note place="margin">A. Int. 37.</note>
                           <hi>Nevile</hi> to his remembrance.</p>
                        <p>They were to his best remembrance delivered sealed up in a Box to <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s man <hi>William Hawet.</hi>
                           <note place="margin">
                              <hi>Court of War</hi> 7. Int. 17. A. Int. 20.</note>
                        </p>
                        <p>He remembers not whether they were left on the Table, or in the room with the Writings of <hi>Fenton</hi> or no.</p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Note.</hi> The Interrogatorie is, Were they left in the room whilst you stayed there, or were they taken away, and by whom? Will not this Witnesse swear any thing?</p>
                     </div>
                     <div n="4" type="item">
                        <head>
                           <hi>4.</hi> In the number of the times of his being at the sealing of Writings at <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s house.</head>
                        <p>He never met with the said Witnesses,<note place="margin">A. Int. 7.</note> nor ever was at the sealing of any other Writings at the house of the said <hi>G. Copley</hi> at any other time, but at the time aforesaid. <hi>viz.</hi> 10. <hi>December</hi> 1632,</p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Contrar.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>The Conveyance of <hi>Fenton</hi> was sealed 10. <hi>Decemb.</hi> 8. <hi>Car.</hi> the Release the 13. of the same Month,<note place="margin">S<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                                 <desc>•</desc>
                              </gap>. <hi>Gerv. Cut<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                    <desc>•…</desc>
                                 </gap>
                              </hi> D. 59. Int. 5 <hi>Tho. Walker</hi> B. 75. Int.<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                                 <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                              </gap>
                           </note> and Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi> was not there the latter time.</p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Thomas Walker</hi> saw <hi>John Swinden</hi> twice there about sealing of Writings concerning <hi>Fenton.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>John Swinden</hi> is a Witnesse to the sealing and delivering of the Conveyance and Release of <hi>Fenton,</hi> as will appear by the Deeds if produced, as is prayed <hi>Scio quia vidi.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>Is not this an absolute Perjury?</p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Note,</hi> That <hi>Hugh Everard,</hi> and <hi>John Swinden,</hi> (the last two witnesses) are thus further infringed.</p>
                        <p n="1">1.<note place="margin">
                              <hi>Ellen Nevile</hi> C. 1. Int. 2</note> They were not certain whether their names subscribed to the said Lease were of their own hand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>writing, or no, when the Defendant <hi>Hawet</hi> first shewed it to them, Insomuch that <hi>Hawet</hi> left it with them to consider of it.</p>
                        <p n="2">2. <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> afterwards drunk a Peece with them at <hi>Barnesly,</hi> and made them merry,<note place="margin">St. <hi>Ioh. Waids<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                    <desc>•…</desc>
                                 </gap>
                              </hi> B. 20. Int. 6. <hi>Ro. Bladen</hi> B. 41. Int.</note> and then they remembred very well.</p>
                        <p n="3">3. <hi>Hugh Everard</hi> and <hi>John Swinden</hi> at <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Office finding at <hi>Wakefield,</hi> deposed that they could not tell to whom <hi>G. Copley</hi> delivered the said Lease, yet four years after they depose positively, that he delivered it to <hi>Francis Nevile.</hi>
                        </p>
                     </div>
                  </div>
                  <div n="3" type="subsection">
                     <head>
                        <hi>3. James Moseley</hi> a third witnesse to <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s <hi>Lease.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <p>
                        <hi>G. Copley</hi> and <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> in <hi>Decemb.</hi> 8. <hi>Car.</hi>
                        <note place="margin">
                           <hi>Iames Mosely</hi> B. 101. Int. 1.</note> sealed and delivered the Conveyance of <hi>Fenton</hi> to <hi>Hugh Everard</hi> and <hi>John Swinden</hi> (parties trusted to receive it) to the use of Sir <hi>Gervas Cutler</hi> his Sister, which occasioned then his being at <hi>Sprotbrough.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>He, <hi>Everard, Swinden, Soreby,</hi> and some others, whose names he hath forgotten,<note place="margin">Int. 2.</note> w<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ere witnesses to several Writings then and there sealed and delivered by <hi>G. Copley</hi> to <hi>Francis Nevile.</hi> He was never at <hi>Sprotbrough</hi> when any writings were there sealed but that one time aforesaid.</p>
                     <p>He was a witnesse to certain writings then and there sealed and delivered by <hi>G.</hi>
                        <note place="margin">
                           <hi>Iames Mosel<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                 <desc>•…</desc>
                              </gap>
                           </hi> L. 57. Int.<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                              <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                           </gap>
                        </note>
                        <hi>Copley</hi> to the use of <hi>Francis Nevile, Everard, Swinden,</hi> and <hi>Soreby,</hi> were witnesses to them. <hi>Thomas Denton</hi> was then pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sent. He and <hi>Everard</hi> conceived them to be matters of secrecy.</p>
                     <p>He verily believes in his Conscience, that <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s Lease was sealed by <hi>G.</hi>
                        <note place="margin">Int. 3.</note>
                        <hi>Copley</hi> at <hi>Sprotbrough</hi> in his presence. He verily believes in his Conscience that his name endorsed thereon as a witnesse is of his proper hand writing. He doth believe in his Conscience that the names of <hi>Hugh Everard, John Swinden,</hi> and <hi>Robert Soreby,</hi> endorsed upon it as witnesses, are of their, and every of their proper hand writing.</p>
                     <p>He wrote his name to all the writings sealed and delivered at <hi>Sprotbrough</hi> betwixt Mr. <hi>Copley,</hi> Mr.<note place="margin">B. 101. Int. 2<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>
                        </note>
                        <hi>Ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vile</hi> and Sir <hi>Gervas Cutler</hi>'s Sister, which were read over, and not read over with one and the same Pen and Ink, and at one and the same time.</p>
                     <p>All the said writings were not sealed at one and the same time,<note place="margin">Int. 3.</note> but there was some intermission of time between their sealing. <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Writings were last sealed after those to the use of Mrs. <hi>Cutler,</hi> but what they were he doth not know. <hi>G. Copley</hi> said unto him, and <hi>Hugh Everard</hi> desiring to know the Contents thereof, that they were matters of Secresie between him and his Cousin <hi>Nevile</hi> the Defendant, so they did not read them nor hear them read.</p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>G. Copley</hi> delivered the said Lease to the said <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> himself in person, and to his use,<note place="margin">Int. 27.</note> and by it self, and not with any other Writings.</p>
                     <p>To whom the said <hi>G. Copley</hi> delivered those Writings of secresie not read, he doth not know,<note place="margin">Int. 14.</note> but is verily perswaded they were delivered to Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi>'s use.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="subsection">
                     <head>Reply.</head>
                     <p n="1">1.<note place="margin">B. Int. 29.</note> He saith that he hath no other reason to induce him to depose that <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s Lease now shewed unto him was sealed and delivered by the said <hi>G. Copley,</hi> but that he believeth the Name <hi>James Mosely</hi> thereunto endorsed is of his own proper hand writing.</p>
                     <p n="2">2. His Contradictions or Perjuries.</p>
                     <div n="1" type="item">
                        <head>
                           <hi>1.</hi> In the person to whom it was delivered.</head>
                        <p>They vvere delivered to <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> by <hi>G. Copley.</hi>
                           <note place="margin">B Int. 2<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                 <desc>•…</desc>
                              </gap> Int. 27.</note>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>G. Copley</hi> delivered it to <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> himself in person and to his use, by it self, and not vvith any other vvritings.</p>
                        <pb facs="tcp:207188:10"/>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Contrar.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <note place="margin">
                              <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                                 <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                              </gap> 14.</note>To whom <hi>G. Copley</hi> delivered those Writings of Secresie, he doth not know, but is verely perswaded they were delivered to Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi>'s use.</p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Note.</hi> 1. Is he not a rash witnesse to depose to two <hi>Interr.</hi> that the said Lease was delivered to <hi>Francis Nevile,</hi> and in one of them to himself in person? And yet he knoweth not to whom it was delivered.</p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Note.</hi> 2. Of what Validity is his perswasion, that it was delivered to Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi>'s use, to blast the reputation of an honest Gentleman deceased, and to destroy the fortune of a Child and her relations.</p>
                     </div>
                     <div n="2" type="item">
                        <head>
                           <hi>2.</hi> In the time when the Writings were sealed and delivered.</head>
                        <p>
                           <note place="margin">
                              <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                                 <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                              </gap> 28.</note>He writ his name to all the writings then and there sealed and delivered with one and the same Pen and Ink, and at one and the same time.</p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Contrar.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <note place="margin">
                              <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                 <desc>•…</desc>
                              </gap>nt 3.</note>All the said Writings were not sealed at one and the same time, but there was some Intermission of time between the sealings.</p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Note.</hi> Is not this <hi>Oppositum in apposito?</hi> How could he set his hand to them all as a witnesse at one and the same time, when they were not sealed at one and the same time?</p>
                     </div>
                     <div n="3" type="item">
                        <head>
                           <hi>3.</hi> He and <hi>Swinden</hi> contradict one another in the time of their sealing and delivering, and which was first, and which was last sealed and delivered.</head>
                        <p>
                           <note place="margin">
                              <hi>
                                 <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                    <desc>•…</desc>
                                 </gap>es Mosely</hi> Int. 3.</note>
                           <hi>James Moseley</hi> saith that all the writings were not sealed at one and the same time, but there was some intermission of time between the sealings, and that <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s writings were last sealed after those to Mrs. <hi>Cutler</hi> viz. of <hi>Fenton.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Contrar.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <note place="margin">
                              <hi>
                                 <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                    <desc>•…</desc>
                                 </gap>n Swinden</hi> 48. Int. 9. <hi>
                                 <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                    <desc>•…</desc>
                                 </gap>ra.</hi>
                           </note>
                           <hi>John Swinden</hi> saith that all the writings were then sealed immediately one after another, and that <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s three Leases to <hi>Francis Nevile,</hi> were first sealed and delivered, and <hi>Fenton</hi> Conveyance was last sealed and delivered.</p>
                     </div>
                     <div n="4" type="item">
                        <head>
                           <hi>4.</hi> In the persons of the Trustees for Mrs. <hi>Cutler.</hi>
                        </head>
                        <p>
                           <note place="margin">
                              <hi>
                                 <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                    <desc>•…</desc>
                                 </gap>nes Mosely</hi> Int. 1.</note>
                           <hi>G. Copley</hi> and <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> delivered the Conveyance of <hi>Fenton</hi> to <hi>Everard</hi> and <hi>Swinden</hi> who were parties trusted for Mrs. <hi>Cutler.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Contrar.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <note place="margin">
                              <hi>Everard</hi> A. <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                 <desc>•…</desc>
                              </gap>. Int. 35. <hi>sup. <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                    <desc>•…</desc>
                                 </gap> Denton</hi> E. 6. <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                 <desc>•…</desc>
                              </gap>. 7. <hi>
                                 <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                    <desc>•…</desc>
                                 </gap>nes Mosely</hi>
                              <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                 <desc>•…</desc>
                              </gap> 1. Int. 2. <hi>
                                 <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                    <desc>•…</desc>
                                 </gap>o. Denton</hi>
                              <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                 <desc>•…</desc>
                              </gap> 6. Int. 7. <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                 <desc>•…</desc>
                              </gap>
                              <hi>Everard</hi> A. <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                 <desc>•…</desc>
                              </gap>. Int. 35. <hi>Ioh. <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                    <desc>•…</desc>
                                 </gap>inden</hi> A. 48 <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                 <desc>•…</desc>
                              </gap>t. 35. <hi>supra. <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                    <desc>•…</desc>
                                 </gap>mes Mosely</hi>
                              <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                 <desc>•…</desc>
                              </gap>. 101. Int. 2. <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                 <desc>•…</desc>
                              </gap>onveyance <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                 <desc>•…</desc>
                              </gap>
                              <hi>Fenton</hi> dat. <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                 <desc>•…</desc>
                              </gap>. Decemb. <hi>
                                 <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                    <desc>•…</desc>
                                 </gap>d the Release</hi> 3. Decemb. <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                 <desc>•…</desc>
                              </gap>. Car.</note>
                           <hi>Hugh Everard</hi> and <hi>Thomas Denton</hi> (not <hi>John Swinden</hi>) were parties trusted for Mrs. <hi>Cutlers</hi> Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veyance.</p>
                     </div>
                     <div n="5" type="item">
                        <head>
                           <hi>5.</hi> In <hi>Thomas Denton</hi> being present when <hi>G. Copley</hi> sealed it.</head>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Thomas Denton</hi> was present, when the writings of Secresie were sealed and delivered by <hi>G. Copley.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Contrar.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Thomas Denton</hi> did not then see any other Writings then of <hi>Fenton</hi> sealed and delivered by <hi>G. Copley</hi> for he went away.</p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Thomas Denton</hi> was not then in the Room or present, when <hi>G. Copley</hi> sealed the said Lease.</p>
                     </div>
                     <div n="6" type="item">
                        <head>
                           <hi>6.</hi> In the number of times of his being at the sealing of Writings at <hi>Sprotbrough.</hi>
                        </head>
                        <p>He was never at <hi>Sprotbrough</hi> when any writings were sealed there, but that one time being in <hi>Decemb.</hi> 8. <hi>Car.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Contrar.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>He was there twice <hi>(viz.)</hi> 10. and 13. of the said <hi>Decemb.</hi> when writings were sealed there. The Conveyance and Release of <hi>Fenton</hi> if produced at the hearing (as is prayed by the Petitioners) will shew it, and that he and <hi>John Swinden</hi> are all the witnesses to <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s sealing and delivering of the Release, nor was Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi> there, for other witnesses are set to it upon his sealing and delivery of it, and it bears another date.</p>
                     </div>
                  </div>
                  <div n="4" type="subsection">
                     <head>
                        <hi>4. Robert Soreby</hi> a fourth witnesse to <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s Lease.</head>
                     <p>He deposed for it at <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Office finding at <hi>Wakefield.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <note place="margin">
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>ir <hi>Geo. Went<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                              <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                                 <desc>•…</desc>
                              </gap>orth.</hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>. 14. Int. 2, 3. <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>r. <hi>Edw. Roads</hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>. 19. Int. 2, 3.</note>
                        <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> produced some writing or writings supposed to be made by <hi>G. Copley</hi> at his Office finding at <hi>Wakefield,</hi> but they knew not what writing or writings they were, and there were only three, <hi>Hugh Everard, John Swinden,</hi> and <hi>Robert Sorely,</hi> that then gave evidence, that the writing or writings were sealed and delivered by <hi>G. Copley.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div type="subsection">
                     <head>Reply.</head>
                     <p n="1">1. It's not directly proved that <hi>Soreby</hi> did then give evidence for the Lease in question, for <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> had two other Leases, which he pretended that <hi>G. Copley</hi> had made him then found in the said Office.</p>
                     <p n="2">2. If he did give evidence for it, he knew not the Contents of it, for the other Three witnesses say that <hi>G. Copley</hi> told them it was a matter of secrecy between him and <hi>Francis Nevile,</hi> and that they neither read it nor heard it read. How then could he depose positively for it?</p>
                     <p n="3">3. He deposed for it as the rest do, only because he saw his name endorsed upon it, as a witnesse, and experience teacheth that names have too often been and daily are counterfeited.</p>
                     <p n="4">4. <hi>Robert Soreby</hi>'s Name was endorsed upon the said Lease by the Defendant <hi>Clayton,</hi> after <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Death, and is of the said <hi>Clayton</hi> his running hand writing, as is proved <hi>infra.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p n="5">
                        <note place="margin">
                           <hi>Hen. Flower</hi> M. 43. Int. 8.</note>5. The Petitioners sought for him, but could not find him that they might have examined him.</p>
                     <p n="6">6. <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> did not examine him in this Suit, least perhaps the Petitioners should cross examine him. His own Guilt, Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi>'s Subtilty, or both might well cause his absence.</p>
                  </div>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div n="8" type="section">
               <pb n="9" facs="tcp:207188:11"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>§. 8.</hi> The number of Writings then and there sealed and delivered by <hi>G. Copley</hi> and <hi>Francis Nevile.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>
                  <hi>G. Copley</hi> and <hi>Francis Nevile,</hi>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <hi>Jo. Swind<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>n</hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap> 48. Int. 7. <hi>sup<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </hi>
                  </note> did jointly and severally seal certain writings to the number of five or six, whereunto he, and the other persons aforenamed (except Mr. <hi>Everard</hi> to the Conveyance of <hi>Fen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ton</hi>) did endorse their names as witnesses.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Note,</hi> This number were then sealed and delivered by them, besides this said Lease, and his other two Leases, found in <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Office, as will thus appear.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>G. Copley</hi> did then and there seal and deliver three or four writings to <hi>Hugh Everard</hi> and <hi>Tho.</hi>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <p>
                        <hi>Tho. Denton</hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                           <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                        </gap> 6. Int. 7. <hi>Hugh Everar<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>
                        </hi> A. 13. Int. 2<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <hi>supra.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Peter Levet</hi> I<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap> 38. Int. 25. <hi>su<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap> Francis Nevil<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap> Letter to the<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                              <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                           </gap> Lady</hi> Porting<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ton. 18. <hi>Decem<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap> supra.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> Inter. to Sir<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                           <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <hi>Waidson</hi> G. 1<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap> Int. 9.</p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Thomas Proct.</hi> F. 1. Int. 5. Sr. <hi>Jo. Waidso<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>
                        </hi> B. 20. Int. 8. <hi>s<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap> J. Swinden</hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                           <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                        </gap> 48. Int. 38. <hi>su<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>
                        </hi>
                     </p>
                  </note>
                  <hi>Denton</hi> for Mrs. <hi>Cutlers</hi> use.</p>
               <p>Two or three writings were then and there sealed by them, which concerned <hi>Newmillerdame</hi> and its Counterpart.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Note, John Swinden</hi>'s number is already proved, Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi> will make them as many more.</p>
               <p>The Reversion of the Lands out of which the Lady <hi>Portington</hi> had a Rent charge, my Cousin <hi>Copley</hi> hath given me.</p>
               <p>The Advowson of the Parsonage of <hi>Sprotbrough</hi> made by <hi>G. Copley</hi> to <hi>Francis Nevile.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>The Advowson of the Parsonage of <hi>Plumtree</hi> made by <hi>G. Copley</hi> to <hi>Francis Nevile,</hi> which <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> shewed to Sir <hi>John Waidson</hi> after <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Death, with but two witnesses to it, <hi>Thomas Wal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ker</hi> and <hi>Richard Elton,</hi> and afterwards with the increase of the other four witnesses.</p>
               <p>The Lease in question, and <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s other two Leases, found in <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Office, added to these, doubleth <hi>John Swinden</hi>'s number that he deposed for.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Note,</hi> If all these be produced (as the Petitioners humbly pray) they will further manifest the For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gery of the said Lease, they will appear all in one dresse <hi>(viz.)</hi> to be of one date or thereabouts, of one hand writing, and of the Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi>'s hand writing, all sealed with one seal, but (not with <hi>G. Copleys</hi>) all attested with the same witnesses; and then <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s three Leases will be multi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plied like his witnesses into six, and his witnesses will be thereby confounded, who have deposed but for three writings then sealed and delivered by <hi>G. Copley</hi> to <hi>Francis Nevile.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="9" type="section">
               <head>
                  <hi>§. 9.</hi> The writings then and there sealed by <hi>G. Copley</hi> to <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> were matters of Secresie between them.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>James Mosely</hi> desired to know the Contents of the Writings to which he subscribed his hand as a wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nesse, and so did Mr. <hi>Everard,</hi> but the said Mr.<note place="margin">
                     <hi>Ja. Moseley</hi> I<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> 101. Int. 3. <hi>su<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </hi>
                  </note>
                  <hi>Copley</hi> replied they were matters of Secresie between him and his Cousin <hi>Nevile</hi> the Defendant.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Note</hi> 1. If those Writings not read, were matters of Secresie between them, <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> then knew their Contents and what they were; But <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> knew not of said his Lease till after <hi>G.</hi>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <hi>Nich. Broadley</hi> A. 4. Int. 53. <hi>Bryan Cooke</hi> I<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> 8. Int. 53. <hi>Will. Berks.</hi> A 108. Int. 24. <hi>Will. Neschall</hi> E. 15. Int. 2. <hi>Peter Levet</hi> E 38. Int. 24. 25 <hi>Will. Key</hi> D. 6. Int. 1. <hi>Emma Mote.</hi> D. 69. I. 6. <hi>supra</hi> Inter. this</note>
                  <hi>Copley</hi>'s death, at least a year after those writings of secresie were sealed; <hi>Ergo,</hi> they were other writings and not his said Lease which were matters of Secresie.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Note</hi> 2. The Writings of Secresie then sealed and delivered by <hi>G. Copley</hi> and <hi>Francis Nevile,</hi> were acknowledged by <hi>Hugh Everard</hi> only to concern <hi>Newmillerdame</hi> and its Counterpart, and that <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> had made a Conveyance of it to <hi>G. Copley,</hi> in lieu and satisfaction of his the said <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s joyn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing with <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> in the sale of <hi>Fenton</hi> to Mrs. <hi>Cutler.</hi> This is proved by these five witnesses.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Note</hi> 3. <hi>G. Copley</hi> in likelyhood to conceal <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s being engaged to him (having then sold <hi>Fenton</hi> and <hi>Newmillerdames</hi> Conveyance to be made to him by <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> in lieu of it) told the wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nesses they were matters of secresie between them; <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> by this passage deluded four of his Witnesses.</p>
               <p n="4">4. <hi>Interrogate</hi> at the hearing, if the Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi> hath not acknowledged that he and <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> by the Counterpart of the Conveyance of <hi>Newmillerdame</hi> (after many tryals to write <hi>G. Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pley</hi>'s and the six witnesses names, and because they could not write so well as <hi>Hugh Everard</hi>'s name was written to it) set to it some of the witnesses names at the first time (which as Sir <hi>John Waidson</hi> hath de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>posed, were <hi>Thomas Walker</hi>'s and <hi>Richard Elton</hi>'s) and afterwards <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> writ the three witnesses names to his said Lease, which are in a kind of a Roman hand, and be the said <hi>Clayton</hi> writ the other three witnesses names to it, which are written upon it in a Secretary hand? or did not the said <hi>Clayton</hi> acknow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge to you some or what words to this effect?</p>
            </div>
            <div n="10" type="section">
               <head>
                  <hi>§. 10. Francis Nevile</hi>'s Lease is not sealed with <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Seal of Arms, with which he always sealed his writings, and said that he never would seal any but with it, nor is his Name to it of his own hand writing.</head>
               <div n="1" type="part">
                  <head>
                     <hi>1. G. Copley</hi> would never seal any writing but with his seal of Arms, and desired Mr. <hi>James Pinckney</hi> to disavow any writing produced after his death at his Act and Deed if not so sealed.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>G. Copley</hi> sealed a Statute to him with his Ring, with four several Coats of Arms upon it,<note place="margin">
                        <hi>Tho. Vincent</hi> A. 1. Int. 127</note> and he then said to him that he never used to seal any writings but with that Seal. The Impression of the Seal to <hi>Fran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cis Nevile</hi>'s Lease in his judgement is not the Impression of the said Seal.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>G. Copley</hi> said to Mr. <hi>James Pinckney,</hi> offering him a seal to seal a Tenants Lease,<note place="margin">
                        <hi>Ann Walker</hi> A. 141. Int. 192.</note> because he had not his own upo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> him, you shall not, for I will never seal any Lease or other writing but with my own Signet; saying further to him, If you overlive me, and any writing shall be produced as my Act and Deed, and the same not sealed with my seal of Arms, I pray you disavow it to be my Act and Deed, for my Signet and hand shall al<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ays go together. And <hi>G. Cpoley</hi> thereupon sent her into his Chamber, and she fetched
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:207188:12"/> him his sealed Ring, and he then and there told Mr. <hi>Pinckney,</hi> that he would never seal any Lease or Deed but it should be sealed with that Signet, for his hand together with that seal, should ever go along at all writings which he sealed.</p>
               </div>
               <div n="2" type="part">
                  <head>
                     <hi>2. G. Copley</hi> sealed all the writings which he sealed (when <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> pretendeth that his Lease was sealed by him) with his Ring Seal of Arms.</head>
                  <p>All the said writings which the said <hi>G. Copley</hi> sealed as aforesaid at <hi>Sprotbrough</hi> were sealed with one and the same Seal,<note place="margin">
                        <hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>n Swinden</hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>8. Int. 16. <hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>h. Elton</hi> A. <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>5. Int. 16. <hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>n Nevile</hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap> 1. Int. 8.</note> which he thinketh was a Ring.</p>
                  <p>All the writings which the said <hi>G. Copley</hi> sealed at the time aforesaid, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap> sealed with his own Seal, which had his Coat of Arms upon it, and was in a Ring which he com<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap> carried at his purse.</p>
                  <p>Mr. <hi>Godfrey Copley</hi> always sealed all writings that ever she saw him sea<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>th his Seal of Arms, and therefore she believeth that he sealed all the writings he then and there sealed with his Seal of Arms, and as she well remembreth he then pulled out his Purse, whereunto was his Ring with his Seal of Arms af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fixed to the string thereof, and with that Seal he sealed those writings she then saw him seal.</p>
                  <p>
                     <note place="margin">
                        <hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>mas Walker</hi> 75. Int. 2.</note>All the Writings which were sealed by <hi>G. Copley</hi> in his presence whereunto he was a witnesse, were sealed with one and the same Seal, being with his the said Mr. <hi>Copley</hi>'s seal of Arms, and he doth very well remember, that to seal the said Writings, he pulled out his Purse, to the String whereof was fixed a Ring, wherein was engraven his Seal of Arms, and which seal he usually carried about him; and with which seal he sealed the said writings, and he took good notice thereof, and well remembreth that there was a good sum of money in the said Purse.</p>
               </div>
               <div n="3" type="part">
                  <head>
                     <hi>3.</hi> Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi>'s Lease is not sealed with <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Seal of Arms, nor is his name upon it of his own hand writing. Nor hath <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> examined a witnesse to prove the Seal or hand to be <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s.</head>
                  <p>
                     <note place="margin">
                        <hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>lph Beomont</hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap> 86. Int. 127</note>
                     <hi>G. Copley</hi> when he sealed him a Lease, called for his own seal, with which he sealed it, and the Impres<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sion of that seal is not like to the Impression of the seal to the writings now shewed to him.</p>
                  <p>
                     <note place="margin">
                        <hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>nuel Bower</hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap> 172. Int. 7.</note>He doth not believe that the Impression of the Seal affixed to the writing to him now shevved, is the Impression of the seal of Arms of the said <hi>G. Copley,</hi> vvherevvith he did usually seal such Writings as he hath seen him seal, since he vvas acquainted vvith him.</p>
                  <p>
                     <note place="margin">
                        <hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>m. Hastings</hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>m. 53. Int.</note>Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi>'s Lease vvhen he first savv it, vvas not sealed vvith the usual seal of Arms, vvherevvith the said <hi>G. Copley</hi> used to seal his other Conveyances and Leases, nor vvherevvith he sealed the Petitioners Leases, but vvith some other seal.</p>
                  <p>
                     <note place="margin">
                        <hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>n Nevile</hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap> 1. Int. 12.</note>The Impression vvherevvith this seal is pressed, neither is, nor ever vvas the Impression of <hi>G. Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pley</hi>'s seal of Arms, vvherevvith he sealed the Conveyance of <hi>Fenton,</hi> she doth not knovv nor believe that this Deed vvas sealed and delivered by the said <hi>G. Copley</hi> to the said <hi>Francis Nevile.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <note place="margin">
                        <hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>an Smith</hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap> 188. Int. 31.</note>The seal affixed to the Writing novv to him shevved, is not the seal of Arms of the said <hi>G. Copley.</hi> Nei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther doth he believe that the name of <hi>Godfrey Copley</hi> undervvritten to the said Writing novv shevved unto him, vvas of the said <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s ovvn hand vvriting. And he the better knovveth so to depose, for that he served the said <hi>G. Copley</hi> as his Butler and Clerk three years together.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Note,</hi> Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi>'s Guilt vvas so great, as he durst not examine a Witnesse to prove the hand or seal to be <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s.</p>
                  <q>Non testes, sed testimonia rerum Judicis conscientiam informare debent.</q>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div n="11" type="section">
               <head>
                  <hi>§. 11.</hi> Who writ <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s said Lease and his <hi>Yorkshire</hi> Leases, and when, and where and what was given or promised for writing them?</head>
               <div n="1" type="part">
                  <head>
                     <hi>1. Francis Nevile</hi> knows not who writ them, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <note place="margin">
                        <hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>ancis Nevile</hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>am. 18. Int.</note>
                     <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> knovveth not vvho vvrit his said Lease, not vvhen nor where it was written, nor who procured it to be written; neither doth he know whether the Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi> writ it or not, nor what reward was given or promised for the writing thereof.</p>
                  <p>
                     <note place="margin">
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>t. 24.</note>He doth not know that the said Lease was vvritten by the same man that ingrossed another Lease of the same date, made to him by the said <hi>G. Copley,</hi> of the Demeasnes of <hi>Sprotbrough</hi> and other Lands for Tvventy one years.</p>
               </div>
               <div n="2" type="part">
                  <head>
                     <hi>2.</hi> The Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi> did not write the said Lease, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <note place="margin">
                        <hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>ill. Claxton</hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>x<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>m. 1. Int. 2.</note>
                     <hi>William Clayton</hi> did not vvrite the said Lease, nor doth he knovv, vvhen or vvhere it vvas vvritten or vvho procured it to be vvritten, nor had he any Revvard given nor promised for vvriting it.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Note,</hi> That <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> and <hi>William Clayton</hi> have perjured themselves, and that his said Lease, and his other tvvo Leases found in <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Office, are of <hi>William Clayton</hi>'s hand-Writing, and vvere vvritten by him after <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s death, as vvill thus appear.</p>
               </div>
               <div n="1" type="part">
                  <head>
                     <hi>1. Francis Nevile</hi> knows the Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi>'s hand writing.</head>
                  <p>
                     <note place="margin">
                        <hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>er Gleidhill</hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap> 101. Int. 1.</note>
                     <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> and the Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi> have been of long acquaintance, and <hi>Nevile</hi> hath employed <hi>Clayton</hi> in many of his Affairs, and in vvriting for him, and in Suits of Lavv, and he believes in his conscience that he is vvell acquainted with <hi>Clayton</hi>'s hand writing.</p>
                  <p>
                     <note place="margin">
                        <hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>ger Ap John</hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>. 50. Int. 24.</note>The Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi> hath made some Leases for <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s Tenants, and he believes that <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> knows his hand writing, and <hi>Clayton</hi> made a Conveyance of a Cottage or two, which Mr. <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> purchased.</p>
               </div>
               <div n="2" type="part">
                  <head>
                     <hi>2.</hi> The Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi> writ <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s said Lease, and his <hi>Yorkshire</hi> Leases after <hi>G. Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pley</hi>'s death, and <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> took them from him, without seals at them, and promised him <hi>40 l. per annum</hi> for it, but not performing it; and for his the said <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s Arresting Mr. <hi>Sunder<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land</hi> for <hi>200 l.</hi> being <hi>Clayton</hi>'s Surety to him, <hi>Clayton</hi> revealed it. But <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> hearing of it reconciled himself to him by Gifts and Loans of money to him and his Wife, and by freeing him from Arrests, and releasing of his own Letter of Attorney, to sue the said <hi>Clayton.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <pb n="11" facs="tcp:207188:13"/>
                  <p>Shee heard the Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi> say, that since the Death of <hi>G. Copley,</hi>
                     <note place="margin">
                        <hi>Ellen Nev<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>
                        </hi> C. 1. Int.</note> he had <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                     <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>rancis Nevile</hi> good Service as concerning <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Lands in <hi>Nottinghamshire,</hi> and as concerning a Lease of <hi>Sprot<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>brough,</hi> and that <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> had promised him 40. <hi>l. per Annum</hi> for it, but now his turn was served, he slighted him, and would not perform his promise, nor do him any other courtesie.</p>
                  <p>The Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi> said, that Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi> then took from him the said Writings.<note place="margin">Int. 16.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>She heard the said <hi>Clayton</hi> say, that he had made Leases of the said <hi>G.</hi>
                     <note place="margin">Int. 17.</note>
                     <hi>Copley</hi>'s Lands in <hi>York-shire</hi> and <hi>Nottinghamshire</hi> for <hi>Francis Nevile.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>He hath at several times heard the Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi> say,<note place="margin">
                        <hi>Peter Glei<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>
                        </hi> C. 101. In<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </note> that he had been imployed by and for the Defendant <hi>Nevile,</hi> as well in <hi>Nottinghamshire</hi> as elsewhere abroad, and complained that <hi>Francis Ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vile</hi> neglected him, saying, that now Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi> had got his own ends, he would do nothing for him. The occasion of these Speeches was, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>his demanding of <hi>Clayton</hi> 200 <hi>l.</hi> which Mr. <hi>Sunderland</hi> had paid to Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi> for the said <hi>Clayton.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>The Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi> after <hi>Christmas</hi> was Twelve months, at <hi>Isaac Wormall</hi>'s house,<note place="margin">
                        <hi>Thomas Bre<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>
                        </hi> A. 47. Int.<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                           <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </note> being told that he dealt ill with Mr. <hi>Sunderland</hi> to suffer him to be taken in execution, being but a Surety for him to Mr. <hi>Nevile;</hi> He answered that <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> had no reason so to prosecute Mr. <hi>Sunderland,</hi> for he had given him the Defendant <hi>Nevile</hi> directions to make Writings, whereby he had got into his Purse 7000 <hi>l.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>The Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi> said to him (telling him how the Defendant <hi>Nevile</hi> exclaimed of him to him) It's best for Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi> to be quiet or else I will tell. He heard the said <hi>Clayton</hi> say, that Mr.<note place="margin">
                        <hi>Thomas Rat<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>
                        </hi> C. 118. Int.<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                           <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </note>
                     <hi>Nevile</hi> had setled 10 <hi>l.</hi> a year upon his Wife if he the said <hi>Clayton</hi> should dye before her. And that the Defen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dant <hi>Nevile</hi> had sent him a 100 <hi>l.</hi> for a Stock.</p>
                  <p>He about four years since was bound to <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> for the Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi> at his request for 50 <hi>l.</hi>
                     <note place="margin">
                        <hi>Samuel King</hi> A. 63. Int. 1<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </note> principal Debt, and at <hi>Clayton</hi>'s perswasion they then gave a Warrant of Attorney to acknowledge Judge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments upon it, and <hi>Nevile</hi> then lent but 20. <hi>l.</hi> whereof he this Deponent had only 5 <hi>l.</hi> but <hi>Francis Ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vile</hi> promised the other 30. <hi>l.</hi> when they came into the Country, and to pay the one half to the one, and the other half to the other, but he never paid any to him, nor to <hi>Clayton</hi> that he knew of, and shortly af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter the money was due, <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> took out Execution against this Deponent who paid <hi>Francis Ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vile</hi> 59 <hi>l.</hi> in discharge thereof.</p>
                  <p>The Defendants <hi>Nevile</hi> and <hi>Clayton</hi> have been long acquainted,<note place="margin">
                        <hi>Robert <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>enso</hi> C. 50. Int. 1</note> and the said <hi>Nevile</hi> hath much be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>friended him, and freed him from some Debts for which he hath been arrested, and the Defendant <hi>Ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vile</hi> hath employed the said <hi>Clayton</hi> in his Suits of Law, and he verily believeth that the Defendant <hi>Nevile</hi> doth well know the Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi>'s hand writing.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Henry Kitchen</hi> was bound with the Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi> to pay a certain summe of money (but how much he knoweth not) to <hi>Francis Nevile,</hi> and being sued for it, Mr.<note place="margin">Int. 29.</note>
                     <hi>Medcalfe</hi> paid it for <hi>Kitchen</hi> to <hi>Nevile.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi> made a Letter of Attorney to the said Mr.<note place="margin">Int. 30.</note>
                     <hi>Medcalfe</hi> to sue the said Bond against the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendant <hi>Clayton,</hi> and before the Tryal he made a Release or some other Act, which troubled Mr. <hi>Med<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>calfe</hi> and put him to much charge.</p>
                  <p>He heard the Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi> say, he could have what money he would of the Defendant <hi>Nevile,</hi>
                     <note place="margin">
                        <hi>Thomas Ratcl<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>
                        </hi> C. 118. Int. 2<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </note> for that he had done him a courtesie.</p>
                  <p>He being in company with Mrs. <hi>Ellen Nevile,</hi> at her Chamber in <hi>Grayes-Inne-lane,</hi>
                     <note place="margin">
                        <hi>Robert Lund</hi> A. 127. Int. 4<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </note> heard the Defen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dant <hi>Clayton</hi> then and there tell her that he writ Three Leases of all <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Lands for the Defendant <hi>Francis Nevile:</hi> But he said that he never saw them either sealed or delivered, nor said he who writ the wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nesses names thereunto, but said that the Defendant <hi>Hawet</hi> could tell, and he then said that he writ the said Leases after the death of the said <hi>G. Copley.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>He heard the Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi> say,<note place="margin">
                        <hi>Thomas Ratcli<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>
                        </hi> C. 118. Int. 1<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </note> he could produce the man that did write the Lease now in question if need should require.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Obadiah Martin</hi> and the Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi> at <hi>Marr</hi> shortly after <hi>Michaelmas</hi> last,<note place="margin">
                        <hi>Lewis Wiggan</hi> A. 126. Int. 5<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </note> being taking of divers Leases which Mr. <hi>Copley</hi> of <hi>Sprotbrough</hi> had made to the Defendant <hi>Nevile,</hi> asked him his name, and he told him <hi>Clayton;</hi> whereupon <hi>Martin</hi> replied, Are not you the man that made the forged Lease of <hi>Plumtree</hi> and other Lands, which the said <hi>Nevile</hi> claimeth to have from the said <hi>G. Copley?</hi> where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>unto the said <hi>Clayton</hi> answered that he was the man that made the said Lease as aforesaid, further saying that he had made many Leases for the said <hi>Nevile,</hi> which he never saw sealed. And also then said, the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plainant had taken a wrong course to make him a Defendant in his Suit, but if he had made him a witness and not a party, he would have spoken truth and done him more good therein.</p>
               </div>
               <div n="3" type="part">
                  <head>
                     <hi>3.</hi> The Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi> said he would deny that he writ the said Lease, because he was made a Party, and he was not bound by Common Law to accuse himself, and a Divine had told him, he might dispense with his Oath in that Case, and it was the safest way to save his ears.</head>
                  <p>The Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi> came to his house at <hi>Marr</hi> in <hi>October</hi> last,<note place="margin">
                        <hi>Thomas Lewis</hi> B. 43. Int. 1.</note> and there of himself speaking of this Suit, told him, that Dr. <hi>Levett</hi> had made him a Party, and said that thereby he would overthrow his Cause, for if he had reserved him for a witness, and made him no party, he said he could, and would then have done him good, and that no body else could do it but himself, and did intreat him to acquaint Dr. <hi>Livett</hi> with so much, and said then he would do him good; and his Wife could also be a witnesse for him, but if he continued him as a party, then he was not bound to accuse himself neither by the Common Law, nor by the Divine Law: For he had talked with a Divine to that purpose, who told him that he might in such a case dispense with his Oath, because it concerned himself as a party, and desired him also to ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quaint the said Doctor with so much; which this Deponent was unwilling to do, they being both his friends, lest he should be brought in as a witnesse, yet the said <hi>Clayton</hi> did urge him to do it, although he told him that nevertheless he thought the said Doctor would make him a Defendant, whereupon the said <hi>Clayton</hi> answered, that if he did he would deny all.</p>
                  <pb n="12" facs="tcp:207188:14"/>
                  <p>
                     <note place="margin">
                        <hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>iah Martin</hi> 122. Int. <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>.</note>The Defend<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="3 letters">
                        <desc>•••</desc>
                     </gap>
                     <hi>Clayton</hi> shortly after <hi>Michaelmas</hi> last, came to Mr. <hi>Lewis</hi> his house in <hi>Marr,</hi> where he heard the said <hi>Clayton</hi> intreat the said Mr. <hi>Lewis</hi> to move the Complainant Dr. <hi>Levett,</hi> that he would produce him as a witnesse, and not make him a party to this Suit, further saying that if he was made a party, he would deny all the Charges that were or should be objected against him in the said Bill. And fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther then said that he had had conference with a Divine about the same, who had advised him so to do, and told him that he was not bound to betray himself in his Answer, if he was made a Party to the said Suit, and therefore he the said <hi>Clayton</hi> was fully resolved not to swear or do any thing to hurt or prejudice the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendant <hi>Nevile</hi> or his Leases: But said that if he had not been made a Party, but been produced as a wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nesse in this Cause, he would have sworn the Truth.</p>
                  <p>
                     <note place="margin">
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                           <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                        </gap>. 142.</note>He heard the said <hi>Clayton</hi> then say that he was very desirous that the Complainant should not make him any party to this Suit, further then saying, that if he did make him party thereunto, he would absolutely de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny all the several Charges laid against him in the said Bill; but if would forbear to make him a party therein, and produce him as a Witnesse, he would then swear the truth, and both would and could do him good therein.</p>
                  <p>
                     <note place="margin">
                        <hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>onard Wray</hi> 143. Int. <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>1. 142.</note>The Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi> came to his house shortly after <hi>Michaelmas</hi> last, and speaking of this Suit told him that Dr. <hi>Levett</hi> had done himself wrong, to make him the said <hi>Clayton</hi> a Party to the said Suit. But if he had produced him as a Witnesse and not made him a Party, he could and would have done the said Dr. <hi>Levett</hi> some good therein as a Witnesse, further then saying that seeing he was made a Party, he would deny all the Charges objected against him, and this was the safest way to save his ears, and although he had spoken broadly heretofore of that businesse, yet now he would say or answer that he spake it in his drink. And he further then said unto him, that something was included in this little breast of his concer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning that matter, which he would not divulge.</p>
               </div>
               <div n="4" type="part">
                  <head>
                     <hi>4. Francis Nevile</hi>'s said Lease, and his <hi>Yorkshire</hi> Leases (found in <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Office) are of one hand writing, and of the Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi>'s hand writing, and so is sealed and delivered in the presence of, and the names of <hi>Thomas Walker</hi> and <hi>Robert Soreby</hi> upon the said Lease in question are of the Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi>'s running hand writing.</head>
                  <p>
                     <note place="margin">
                        <hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>mon Fawcet</hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>. 113. Int. 19.</note>He was the Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi>'s Brothers Clerk, and is very well acquainted with the Defendant <hi>Clay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ton</hi>'s hand writing, and doth believe that Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi>'s Lease of <hi>Plumtree</hi> is of the hand writing of him the said <hi>William Clayton,</hi> for that the same is written with the very Character of him the said <hi>William,</hi> although some words are made to differ from his hand, and are written with a fuller Letter then he did usu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ally write.</p>
                  <p>
                     <note place="margin">
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>nt. 23.</note>He telling Mr. <hi>John Clayton</hi> (the Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi>'s Brother) that he thought the Complainant would examine him, if he knevv the Lease in question to be of the Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi>'s hand Writing, unto vvhich Mr. <hi>John Clayton</hi> replyed, that there vvas no question but it vvas his hand vvriting.</p>
                  <p>
                     <note place="margin">
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>n<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>. 28.</note>He doth verily believe that the Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi> vvrit the Witnesses names endorsed on the back of the said Lease, named <hi>Thomas Walker</hi> and <hi>Robert Soreby,</hi> being Wtitten in Secretary for that it is very like his running hand.</p>
                  <p>
                     <note place="margin">
                        <hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>ho. Ratcliffe</hi> C. 118 Int. 19.</note>He hath seen divers Writings vvritten by the said <hi>William Clayton</hi> both in paper and parchment, and is well acquainted with his hand Writing. He doth believe that the Writing novv shewed unto him is of the proper hand Writing of him the said <hi>Wiliam Clayton,</hi> for that the Characters of the Letters, and the fullnesse of the hand are very like the Character of him the said <hi>William,</hi> and especially for that the words (sealed and delivered in the presence of) on the backside of the said Writing, are as he believeth in his Conscience, his the said <hi>William Clayton</hi>'s own hand Writing.</p>
                  <p>
                     <note place="margin">Int. 22.</note>He saith that so far forth as possibly one man may know another mans hand Writing that did not see him write it, he knoweth and verely believeth in his Conscience that the Defendant <hi>William Clayton</hi> wrote the Endor<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ement upon the said Lease of <hi>Plumtree.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <note place="margin">Henson Broome Court of Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quests, ex parte Ellen Nevile <hi>fol. 41. Int. 11.</hi>
                     </note>
                     <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> produced three Leases at <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Office finding at <hi>Wakefield,</hi> vvhich vvere found in it to be to his use, and which Leases being vievved by this Deponent, vvere by him conceived to be the hand Writing of the said <hi>William Clayton,</hi> vvho vvas there and then present, vvhose hand Writing he had formerly often seen. This Deponent telling Mr. <hi>John Clayton</hi> (Brother to the Defendant) that he had heard that he had said at <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Office finding: <hi>Will.</hi> These Leases are of thy hand Writing; the said Mr. <hi>John Clayton</hi> gave him this Ansvver, say nothing thereof to Mr. <hi>Nevile.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <note place="margin">
                        <hi>John Clayton</hi> C. 68. Int. 24.</note>He vvas of Council vvith the Defendant Mr. <hi>Francis Nevile,</hi> vvhen the Office vvas found at <hi>Wake<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>field,</hi> after the death of the said <hi>G. Copley,</hi> concerning such lands as he dyed seised of, and did see, read, and peruse the three Leases before metioned, and did conceive them all to be of one hand vvriting, and the said <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> did produce them, and gave them in evidence to the Jury, and he had them in his hands, and did then conceive that they vvere of the hand Writing of the said Defendant <hi>William Clayton.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div n="5" type="part">
                  <head>
                     <hi>5.</hi> Mr. <hi>John Clayton</hi> (the Defendants Brother) knoweth the said Leases to be forged, and for <hi>500 l.</hi> would have discovered it.</head>
                  <p>The Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi>'s Brother (Mr. <hi>John Clayton</hi> Counsellor at Lavv) acknovvledged to M. <hi>Washington</hi> that he knevv a vvay to overthrovv the said Leases,<note place="margin">
                        <hi>Darcy Washing<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ton</hi> B. 55. Int. 2</note> but demanded 500 <hi>l. (viz.)</hi> 300 <hi>l.</hi> in hand, and 200 <hi>l.</hi> to be secured, and offered to engage his Land for repayment, in case they vvere not overthrovvn, and he said it vvas to be done by the Defendant <hi>Clayton.</hi> And <hi>John Clayton</hi> did often im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portune him, and used several Arguments to embrace the said offer and contract.</p>
                  <p>
                     <note place="margin">
                        <hi>Rob. Benson.</hi> C. 50 Int. 20. <hi>Ellen Nevile</hi> C. 1. Int. 18, 43</note>Mr. <hi>John Clayton</hi> said that they vvere executed privately, and there vvere but tvvo or three at the ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ecution of them, or that knevv of it, and that the Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi> vvrit them out of the Instructions vvhich <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> gave him under his ovvn hand.</p>
               </div>
               <div n="6" type="part">
                  <pb n="13" facs="tcp:207188:15"/>
                  <head>
                     <hi>6. Francis Nevile</hi> did not examine the Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi> upon his Lease.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> by an Order of Court examined the Defendant <hi>Clayton de bene esse,</hi>
                     <note place="margin">Order 8. <hi>M</hi> 14. <hi>Car.</hi> Inter. this</note> and did not exa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mine him upon the view of his Lease, whether he writ it or no.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Interrogate.</hi> Did not you hear the Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi> say, that he cared not what Dr. <hi>Levett</hi> could do against him. For he had written the said Lease only for his hire, and <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> took it from him unsealed, and to be sure the Doctor could not perjure him, for he had only denyed that he writ the Lease which Mr. <hi>G. Copley</hi> had made to <hi>Francis Nevile,</hi> let him shew me the Lease in question, and if it be of my hand writing, I writ it about a month after <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s death, and if <hi>G. Copley</hi> could then make it to <hi>Francis Nevile,</hi> I will be hang'd for it, or to this effect.</p>
               </div>
               <div n="7" type="part">
                  <head>
                     <hi>7.</hi> The Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi> knew not what to depose because he saw not the said Lease.</head>
                  <p>The Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi> said, that in regard he could not see <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s Lease,<note place="margin">
                        <hi>Will. Gray</hi> B. Int. 9.</note> he knew not what to swear unto, but if he might see it, he could tell whether he writ it or not.</p>
               </div>
               <div n="8" type="part">
                  <head>
                     <hi>8.</hi> The Lease was not produced into the Court when the Petitioners examined <hi>Clayton.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>The said Lease was not produced into Court when the Petitioners examined the Defendant <hi>Clayton,</hi>
                     <note place="margin">Inter. this.</note> they intended to have examined him <hi>ore tenus</hi> upon view of the said Lease, at the hearing, if it was his hand writing, but <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> sent him into the Country to prevent it, and gave him 100 <hi>l.</hi> (as the said <hi>Clayton</hi> hath since acknowledged) to be absent, as the Petitioners hope to prove.</p>
               </div>
               <div n="9" type="part">
                  <head>
                     <hi>9.</hi> What did <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> give <hi>Clayton</hi> to put in his Answer to the Petitioners Bill?</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Interrogate.</hi> If <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> gave not the Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi> 20. <hi>l.</hi>
                     <note place="margin">Inter. it.</note> in gold to put in his Answer to the Petitioners Bill in the <hi>Star Chamber,</hi> which Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi>'s Counsell had drawn up, without the said <hi>Clayton</hi>'s privity? And did not <hi>Clayton</hi> also shew you the Gold which he said that <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> had given him?</p>
               </div>
               <div n="10" type="part">
                  <head>
                     <hi>10.</hi> Did not the Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi> reveal the Forgery of the said Lease when <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Office was found?</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Interrogate.</hi> If the Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi> said not immediately after <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Office was found,<note place="margin">Inter. this.</note> I will tell you the best Jest that ever you heard. How say you, but <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> and I have written the six wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nesses names, to the three Leases, which Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi> hath produced, pretending them to be made by <hi>G. Copley</hi> unto him, that three of the witnesses have this day deposed, that they writ their names to them with their own hands? Have you ever heard such a jest in all your life time? or spake he any, and what words to this effect?</p>
               </div>
               <div n="11" type="part">
                  <head>
                     <hi>11.</hi> Did not the Defendandant <hi>Clayton</hi>'s Wife warm the Wax in a Pan for to seal the said Leases which were found in <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Office?</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Interrogate.</hi> If the Defendants <hi>Francis Nevile,</hi>
                     <note place="margin">Inter. this.</note> and <hi>William Clayton</hi> did not (when they forged the said Leases) give the said <hi>Clayton</hi>'s Wife wax to warm in a Pan, and whether (she overheating it, or burning it to the Pan side) the said <hi>Nevile</hi> and <hi>Clayton</hi> did not take wax from old Evidences, because the said Leases were antedated about a year, and put it to them? And did not the said <hi>Clayton</hi> then say to <hi>Francis Nevile,</hi> he hoped he would have no swearing for them? To which <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> replyed with an Oath. <hi>(Will.)</hi> dost thou think I am mad? I'll warrant thee no swearing, I have but a couple of Fooles (<hi>Copley</hi> and <hi>Hastings</hi>) to deal with, I will onely shew them the Leases and get a composition of them, and that's all I look for. And did not <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> then carry them away from the said <hi>Clayton</hi> without any seals put to the said wax? or what else was done or spoken then to this effect?</p>
               </div>
               <div n="12" type="part">
                  <head>
                     <hi>12. William Clayton</hi>'s Deed with a clause of Revocation.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Interrogate.</hi> If the Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi> did not shew you a Deed,<note place="margin">Inter. this.</note> which had a clause of Revocation in it, and tell you that by the help of it, he and <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> made the clause of Revocation, which he the said <hi>Clayton</hi> writ in <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s Lease now in question, or to this effect?</p>
               </div>
               <div n="13" type="part">
                  <head>
                     <hi>13.</hi> Did not the Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi> leave the manner of the forgery under his hand, with a Counsellor at Law, to be produced into the Court of <hi>Star Chamber,</hi> in case <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> brought him not off clear?</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Interrogate.</hi> If the Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi> writ not over the whole forgery of the said Lease,<note place="margin">Inter. this,</note> and left it with a Councellor at Law, to produce to the said Court of <hi>Star Chamber,</hi> in case <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> brought him not off then clear, as he had promised him to do; further saying, I have confessed that I did write it after <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s death, and it's proved to be my hand writing, and therefore I expect nothing but a cen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sure; and perhaps his sending of me away, is to lay it upon me, and save himself, if he do, then produce it; for this is the true manner of our forging of it after <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s death.</p>
               </div>
               <div n="14" type="part">
                  <head>
                     <hi>14.</hi> What was the Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi>'s confession of his forging <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s Lease upon his death<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bed?</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Interrogate.</hi> If the Defendant <hi>Clayton</hi> did not in his Sicknesse a little before his death,<note place="margin">Inter. this.</note> say that his making of Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi>'s said Lease, did lye more heavy upon his Soul and Conscience, then all the things he had done in all his Life time. And desired God to spare him but one year longer, and said unto his Wife, thou knowest enough concerning the forgery of it, discharge thy conscience if ever thou shalt be examined about it, or to this effect?</p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div n="12" type="section">
               <head>
                  <hi>§. 12.</hi> How got <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> his said Leases?</head>
               <p>She saith that she heard Mr.<note place="margin">
                     <hi>Eliz. Rogers</hi> B. 3. Int. 10.</note>
                  <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> (being in discourse with her Husband touching his Leases or Estate he claimed from <hi>G. Copley</hi>) say that so he got the said Leases or Estate, he cared not how he got them; Her Husband or some other replied, he hoped he vvould not get them vvith svvearing; but she remem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers not vvhat vvas Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi>'s Ansvver.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Note,</hi> Is it not likely that <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> gave then such an Ansvver as he gave to the Defendant Mr. <hi>Hastings</hi> upon the like Question. <hi>(viz.)</hi> Who would not swear everlastingly for such an estate as that? as is proved in their Combination. <hi>Infra.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="13" type="section">
               <pb n="14" facs="tcp:207188:16"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>§. 13. Francis Nevile</hi>'s Contradiction and Perjury about his first knowledge of the said Lease.</head>
               <div n="1" type="part">
                  <head>
                     <hi>1.</hi> His Contradiction.</head>
                  <p>
                     <note place="margin">
                        <hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>ge Clarke</hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>2. Int. 1.</note>
                     <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> knew of the said Lease before he entred into the Award between the Defendants <hi>Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pley</hi> and <hi>Hastings.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Contrar.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <note place="margin">
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                           <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <hi>Savile</hi> 7. Int. 4 <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <hi>Goodhand</hi> 2. Int. 25.</note>He knew not of it when he made the said Award or Agreement between <hi>Copley</hi> and <hi>Hastings.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>He offered to make good by Oath in the <hi>Court of Wards,</hi> that he knew not of it when he made the said Agreement, and a Book being tendred he was ready to swear. Sir <hi>Walter Pye</hi> then said, he was ei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther a Knave or a Fool to make such an Agreement if he knew the Contents of it.</p>
               </div>
               <div n="2" type="part">
                  <head>
                     <hi>2.</hi> His Perjury.</head>
                  <p>He knew of it before the said Award or Agreement was made.</p>
                  <p>
                     <note place="margin">
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                           <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                        </gap>. <hi>Nevile</hi>'s <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>m. 18. Int.</note>When he did mediate a peace, and end some differences between <hi>William Copley</hi> and <hi>Edmund Hastings</hi> about the said Lease of the Mannor of <hi>Plumtree,</hi> he was not fully satisfied of the validity of his own Lease.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Note,</hi> Then it was in being, and he knew of it. Validity presupposeth both.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Contrar.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <note place="margin">
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                           <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                        </gap>. <hi>Nevile</hi>'s <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>wer Court <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap> Wards to <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>end<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>nt <hi>Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>
                        </hi>'s Bill. fol.</note>He knew not of his said Lease before the said Award or Agreement was made, but found it after.</p>
                  <p>It is very true that after the sealing of the said Articles he did find that he had a Term and Interest amongst other things in the Mannor of <hi>Plumtree,</hi> in the County of <hi>Nottingham,</hi> of which by the said Articles and Agreement the Complainant <hi>Copley</hi> was to make the said <hi>Edmund Hastings</hi> and his Wife a Lease for Twenty one years paying Two pence Rent.</p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div n="14" type="section">
               <head>
                  <hi>§. 14.</hi> Mr. <hi>G. Copley</hi> when he made the Petitioners Leases, made also divers Leases of his <hi>Yorkshire</hi> Lands, some for money, some for reward of Service, and others for love, and all the Tenants enjoy them quietly, notwithstanding <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s former pretended Lease of the said Lands, which he also got found in <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Office.</head>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                     <hi>Shaw</hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>94. Int. <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>, 156, 157. <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>fry Winter</hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>7. Int. 155, <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>, 157.</note>
                  <hi>G. Copley</hi> when he ma<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>e the Complainants Leases, made also a Lease to <hi>Christopher Handly,</hi> for sixty pounds Fine, and the old Rent. He also then made a Lease of his purchased Lands in <hi>Newton,</hi> to <hi>Ed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mund Hastings</hi> and his Wife, to pay to three Servants as a requital of their pains they took with him in his Sicknesse, Ten pounds <hi>per Annum</hi> a piece, and charged Mrs. <hi>Hastings</hi> to pay them, which she promised and vowed to do. He then made two Leases to <hi>Coates,</hi> and a Lease to Mr. <hi>Copley</hi> of <hi>Lover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sall,</hi> and a Lease to <hi>Beaumond</hi> in <hi>Sprotbrough; G. Copley</hi> then caused an Error in one of them to be amen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded, and told <hi>Beaumond</hi> (then desiring a longer time) that if he made it for above twenty one years, or abated him any Rent, it would be void. All which as well of his purchased Lands, as of his other Lands in <hi>Sprotbrough,</hi> are still enjoyed by the several Tenants, notwithstanding the Lease which Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi> produced of the same Lands, as formerly made unto him by the said <hi>G. Copley.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Note</hi> 1. That <hi>G. Copley</hi> being an honest Gentleman, would not have expressed a Requital of pains to his Servants, and have forced Mrs. <hi>Hastings</hi> to promise and vow to pay them, much less have taken his Tenant <hi>Handley</hi>'s 60. <hi>l.</hi> Fine for a Lease, if he had made <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> a former Lease of their Lands.</p>
               <p n="2">2. If <hi>G. Copley</hi> rectified an Error in one of the said Leases, and took such care to prevent <hi>Beaumond</hi>'s Lease from being void. Had he made Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi> a former Lease to make it void?</p>
               <p n="3">3. If <hi>G. Copley</hi> had made Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi> a Lease a year before of the same Lands. Would Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi> have suffered all these Tenants (most of them at the old rent) quietly to enjoy their Leases?</p>
            </div>
            <div n="15" type="section">
               <head>
                  <hi>§. 15. Francis Nevile</hi>'s Reproof of the Defendant <hi>Copley</hi> for troubling <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Will, Leases and Writings lawfully executed and duely made and letten by him before his death.</head>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>an. Nevile</hi>'s <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>swer to De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                     <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ndant <hi>Copleys</hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ll Court of <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>rds fol. 15.</note>By which their secret dealing, combination or confederacies, they or one of them (the said Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plainant, and <hi>Ralph Copley</hi>) troubled all men, that either claimed any thing by the said <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Will, or by Lease or by Writings from him, insomuch as the very Tenants were both threatned and troubled for their Leases and Lands, which were lawfully executed, and duely made and letten by the said <hi>G. Copley</hi> unto them before his death.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Note, Francis Nevile</hi> reproveth the Defendant <hi>Copley</hi> in this his Answer upon Oath, for troubling the Petitioner aswell as others about their Leases, which were lawfully executed, and duly made and let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ten by the said <hi>G. Copley</hi> before his Death.</p>
               <p>How then can he now pretend that his said Lease was made by the said <hi>G. Copley</hi> of the same Lands a year before? <hi>Ex ore tuo te judicabo.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="16" type="section">
               <head>
                  <hi>§. 16. Francis Nevile</hi>'s counterfeited Letter to the Petitioner Dr. <hi>Levett.</hi>
               </head>
               <floatingText type="letter" xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <opener>
                        <salute>Mr. Dr. <hi>Levett;</hi>
                        </salute>
                     </opener>
                     <p>
                        <hi>I</hi> Am your Neighbour and shall ever wish you well, and upon any occasion will be ready to do you faithful Service; be pleased to be advertised by me who am able to give you Counsell, I hear that you have prefer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red a Bill against Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi> of <hi>Cheete</hi> and others in the Star Chamber for forging a Lease of <hi>Plumtree,</hi> and some other Misdemeanors, I am sorry you have gone so far, for I know there hath been too much both said and done in these things already. I know many, or almost all the witnesses to all his Leases, and they have
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:207188:17"/> already sworn to the execution of them. Those that I know which are sworn, are honest, able, and religious men, I have conferred with them, and you will find it impossible to do any good in that matter; if you have any dependency of his Mothers Information, you will find that she will say much, but there is nothing in her but untruth and Inconstancy; believe me, I wish you better then I do all the <hi>Neviles</hi> in <hi>England,</hi> take present course to make your peace, before any further proceedings, or you will be undone. He is your neer Kinsman by Marriage, and I know by Mr. <hi>Bladwin</hi>'s means you may have all things ended by discovering his Accusers, who indeed are your Misinformers, and by Mr. <hi>Bladwin</hi>'s means you may get Sir <hi>William Savile</hi> to end all. It is certain for the Leases you cannot hurt him. I hear he hath an Information ready drawn against his Mother, you, and your Brother, and some others for practises, combinations, and suborna<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions, and some other things about your office; I know he may prove much against his Mother, and some others, but I hope not against you But I pray you for God sake procure peace and speedily, for which I will be your daily Oratour to God, and will daily pray for you, but you shall not know what I am till I hear that you are in peace.</p>
                     <closer>
                        <dateline>
                           <date>
                              <hi>January this first.</hi>
                           </date>
                        </dateline>
                        <signed>T. K.</signed>
                     </closer>
                     <postscript>
                        <p>Md. <hi>That this is a true Copy of a Letter directed to Dr.</hi> Levet, <hi>and exhibited by him in the Court of</hi> Star Chamber, <hi>examined by us whose Names are here underwritten,</hi>
                        </p>
                        <closer>
                           <dateline>
                              <date>
                                 <hi>the 23. of</hi> May <hi>1638.</hi>
                              </date>
                           </dateline>
                           <signed>
                              <list>
                                 <item>James Freke,</item>
                                 <item>Rob. Heyward</item>
                                 <item>Rob. Aylett.</item>
                              </list>
                              <hi>Jur. 25. Decemb. 1646.</hi>
                           </signed>
                        </closer>
                     </postscript>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
               <p>This Letter is thus proved to be <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s hand writing.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Eliz. Rogers (Francis Nevile</hi>'s Aunt) saith, she is acquainted with his hand writing,<note place="margin">
                     <hi>Eliz. Rogers</hi> B 3. Int. 11.</note> and that the Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter dated the first of <hi>January</hi> now shewed her, is in many words, Syllables, and Letters, like Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi>'s hand writing, especially two or three of the last lines thereof.</p>
               <p>He knoweth <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s hand writing, and this Letter now shewed unto him,<note place="margin">
                     <hi>Rob. Benson</hi> C. 50. Int. 12.</note> is somewhat like his hand writing, and the Letters W. and M. especially are very like his Character, but the whole sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stance is not such a hand as he doth usually write, but many of the words in the said Letter contained, are wonderful like the manner of the hand Writing of the Defendant <hi>Francis Nevile.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>The Letter now shewed him, dated the first of <hi>January,</hi>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <hi>James Freke</hi> D. 80. Int. 15</note> is in many Letters so like the Defendant <hi>Nevile</hi>'s hand Writing, <hi>(viz.)</hi> the M. and A. and other Letters, that he doth believe in his conscience, it is the said <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s own hand Writing.</p>
               <p>He is well acquainted with the hand writing of Mr. <hi>Francis Nevile,</hi>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <hi>And Goodhand</hi> D. 1. Int. 9.</note> and believeth that the Letter now shewed him is all, or most part of the said Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi>'s hand Writing, and is the more confirmed in such his belief, because he never saw any man make such an L. M. and N. and divers other Letters in the Writing now shewed him, but the said Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi> himself.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Note</hi> 1. Doth not this Letter shew Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi> to be an Artist both in counterfeiting of writings, and in dissimulation (He loveth Dr. <hi>Levet,</hi> better then he doth all the <hi>Neviles</hi> in England; you shall not know what I am till I hear you are in peace.)</p>
               <p n="2">2. Are not his Advertisement, Counsell, devout prayer (for God sake) and his directions to a peace; and also his forraign plea, (his information for practises, combinations, subornations, and some other things about your Office) arguments of his dread, and Guilt?</p>
            </div>
            <div n="17" type="section">
               <head>
                  <hi>§. 17. Francis Nevile</hi>'s Sale of his said Leases to the Defendants <hi>Mr. Copley</hi> and Mr. <hi>Hastings.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>
                  <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> sold so much of his pretended Leases (had they not been forged) as were worth 20000 <hi>l.</hi> to the Defendant <hi>Copley</hi> for 3200 <hi>l.</hi> and sold to the Defendant <hi>Hastings</hi> the Demeasnes of <hi>Plumtree</hi> for 2650 <hi>l.</hi> above board. But underhand <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> released to him 1800 <hi>l.</hi> of it, as will appear in their combination <hi>Infra.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="18" type="section">
               <head>
                  <hi>§. 18. Francis Nevile</hi> desired a little before <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s death a Lease of his Lands.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> discoursing with <hi>G. Copley</hi> not long before his death about something that <hi>G.</hi>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <hi>Eliz. Rogers</hi> B. 3. Int. 6. <hi>Anthony Gilby</hi> B. 14. Int. 6.</note>
                  <hi>Copley</hi> said he would doe for the Petitioner <hi>Mary,</hi> told him that he had not power to make Leases. Whereupon <hi>G. Copley</hi> called for a Box of Writings, which Mrs. <hi>Nevile</hi> said that she brought him, and <hi>Francis Ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vile</hi> perusing his Deed of power, wished that Mr. <hi>G. Copley</hi> would make him a Lease of all the Lands he had, and see if he would not keep them.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Note</hi> 1. had <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> then a Lease made him by <hi>G. Copley</hi> a year before? if so, then he needed not to have desired one.</p>
               <p n="2">2. If <hi>G. Copley</hi> had made <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> a Lease before, how could he then tell <hi>Francis Nevile,</hi> that he would do something for the Petitioner <hi>Mary?</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="3">3. Why should <hi>G. Copley</hi> then shew <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> his Deed of power to do something for the Peti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioner, if he had executed his power in making <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s Lease a year before?</p>
            </div>
            <div n="19" type="section">
               <head>
                  <hi>§. 19.</hi> Who gave <hi>Francis Nevile,</hi> or delivered into his hands his said Lease, and his two Leases of <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s <hi>Yorkshire</hi> Lands found in his Office? and when?</head>
               <p n="1">1. <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s Witnesses left them lying on the Table,<note place="margin">
                     <hi>Iohn Swinden</hi> A. 48. Int. 20.</note> and know not that <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> carried them away.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>John Swinden</hi> remembers not whether they were left on the Table, or in the Room with the Writings that concerned the Lands in <hi>Fenton</hi> or no.</p>
               <pb n="13" facs="tcp:207188:18"/>
               <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                  <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="14" facs="tcp:207188:19"/>
               <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                  <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="15" facs="tcp:207188:20"/>
               <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                  <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="16" facs="tcp:207188:21"/>
               <p>
                  <hi>Note.</hi> The Iterrogatory is. Were they left in the Room, while you stayed there, or were they taken away, and by whom?</p>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>es Moseley</hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> 101. Int. 30.</note>
                  <hi>James Moseley</hi> knows not, that <hi>Francis Nevile,</hi> or the Defendant <hi>Hawet</hi> carried away with them out of the Room any Writings, which were then sealed, either publiquely or privately.</p>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>t. 15.</note>He left the said Writings on the Table, when he had subscribed his name, but how long they lay there, or what became of them afterwards he knoweth not.</p>
               <p n="2">2. <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> said that his Mother gave them to him at the said Award making.</p>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap>. <hi>Ioh. Waidson</hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> 20. Int. 4.</note>
                  <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> said that his Mother delivered him the said Lease at the very same time when the agree<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment was made between <hi>William Copley</hi> and <hi>Edm. Hastings.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="3">3. <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s Mother knew not that <hi>G. Copley</hi> made the said Lease, nor did she give it to him.</p>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>en Nevile</hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>. 1. Int. 11.</note>
                  <hi>G. Copley</hi> did never make any Lease or Leases of his <hi>Nottinghamshire</hi> Lands and of his Mannor of <hi>Plumtree</hi> to <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> that ever she knew of.</p>
               <p>She gave not <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> the Lease after the Arbitrament betwixt <hi>William Copley</hi> and <hi>Edmund Hastings.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="20" type="section">
               <head>
                  <hi>§. 20. Francis Nevile</hi> desired the Petitioner <hi>Mary</hi> (for a Wife for his Son) and he would recover her the Mannor of <hi>Bentley.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>ervas Rogers</hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>. 88. Int. 172.</note>He heard <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> say, that if the Father of the Petitioner would let him have her (and as he conceived for a Wife for his Son) he would make no question at all but to recover her the Mannor of <hi>Bentley.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>liz. Rogers</hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>. 3. Int. 3.</note>She heard <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> at <hi>Netherthorpe</hi> about half a year after <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s death, say, that if <hi>Mary Mote</hi> (the now Petitioner) was turned over to him, he would recover her the Lordship of <hi>Bentley</hi> or give her as much of his own Lands.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Note.</hi> What title had the Petitioner to the Mannor of <hi>Bentley,</hi> but by these her Leases made by <hi>G. Copley?</hi> If Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi> can make good her Leases for <hi>Bentley,</hi> how can he overthrow them for <hi>Plumtree,</hi> seeing the one aswell as the other is given to her by the same Leases, and there is <hi>par ratio</hi> for them both, <hi>viz.</hi> the meer good will and affection of the Donor Mr. <hi>G. Copley.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="21" type="section">
               <head>
                  <hi>§. 21. G. Copley</hi> would not lease <hi>Plumtree</hi> till his death, for he would not <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ye a Begger.</head>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>llen Nevile</hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>. 1. Int. 10.</note>
                  <hi>G. Copley</hi> about a moneth before his death, being moved by her to make a Lease of <hi>Plumtree</hi> and of his other lands in <hi>Nottinghamshire</hi> to his Cousin <hi>John Copley,</hi> denyed it, saying, he would not dye a Begger, but would keep sometning to give away at his death. He gave Mr. <hi>Iohn Copley,</hi> afterwards moving him to it, the very same answer.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Note.</hi> Had he then made a Lease of <hi>Plumtree</hi> a year befere to Mr. <hi>Nevile?</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="22" type="section">
               <head>
                  <hi>§. 22. G. Copley</hi>'s Protestation, that <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> should not be better for his Estate to the value of a Groate.</head>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>eon. Pinckney</hi> 3. 49. Int. 3.</note>Mr. <hi>G. Copley</hi> said, that <hi>G. Copley</hi> of <hi>Lincolns-Inn,</hi> and <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> of <hi>Cheet,</hi> did rely upon his Estate, and that they would raise their fortunes by it; but the said <hi>G. Copley</hi> of <hi>Sprotbrough</hi> protested in his presence, that neither they, nor either of them, should be the better for any of his Estate to the value of one Groat.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Note, G. Copley</hi> made it good, for neither of them were mentioned in his Will, or any other publick Writing.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="23" type="section">
               <head>
                  <hi>§. 23.</hi> Did <hi>G. Copley</hi> at his death deny that he had ever made <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> any Lease of <hi>Plumtree?</hi>
               </head>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">Inter. this.</note>
                  <hi>Interrogate.</hi> If Mr. <hi>G. Copley</hi> being asked by a Gent. (when he had made the Petititioners Leases) if he had not made a former Lease of the same Lands to Mr. <hi>Boswell</hi> of <hi>Gunthwaite,</hi> or to Mr. <hi>Francis Ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vile</hi> of <hi>Cheet,</hi> answered him, I never made any Lease of them unto them, or either of them in my life, further saying, I know <hi>Frank Nevil</hi> too well to have any dealing with him in any such kind, and did <hi>G. Copley</hi> then charge him as he meant to answer it before God to vindicate his credit about the Petitioners Leases, for he had power to make them, and had lawfully executed them, and had done therein what he desired to doe? or to this effect?</p>
            </div>
         </div>
         <div n="2" type="chapter">
            <head>CHAP. 2.</head>
            <p>THat to countenance this Forgery, and their publishing of the said Forged Lease, which the Defendants <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> and <hi>William Clayton</hi> knew to be Forged, the said <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> by the unlavvfull help of <hi>Iohn Batt</hi> Esq; then Escheator, and by bribing of <hi>Iohn Goodhand</hi> Esquire then Feodary of the West-riding of the said County of <hi>York,</hi> and by the said <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s embracing and bribing of <hi>VVilliam Jenkinson,</hi> and others of the Jury impannelled by the said Escheator (a Jury summoned and returned by the Sheriff then there appearing, but rejected by the said Escheator) corruptly caused an Inquisition aftet the death of the said <hi>G. Copley</hi> to be taken, vvherein the said Leases vvere found and after Forged and un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duely returned that Office also.</p>
            <p n="1">
               <pb n="17" facs="tcp:207188:22"/>1. <hi>John Goodhand</hi> then Feodary, undertook to carry dovvn the <hi>diem clausit extrem</hi>
               <gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>dant <hi>Copley,</hi> but delivered it to the Defendant <hi>Iohn Batt</hi> then Escheator of <hi>York-shire,</hi>
               <gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>fendant <hi>Copley</hi> for vvhom he had sued it out.</p>
            <p n="2">2. The Escheator <hi>Iohn Batt</hi> having got the said <hi>diem clausit</hi> into his hands, found <hi>G.<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> Wakefield</hi> (a peculiar, although it vvas a Country businesse) and refused the Defendant<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> Councell moving him to find it at a more convenient time and place. And <hi>Batt</hi> said he ca<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> to find it, and vvould then find it. And never sate Escheator but that day.</p>
            <p n="3">3. <hi>John Batt</hi> at the instance of <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> and his Counsell, rejected the Jury whic<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> rant the Sheriff had summoned, and which did there appear, and accepted of another then, sum<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> out his Warrant by the Deputy Bailiff of <hi>Wakefield</hi> (the Defendant <hi>William Hawet,</hi>
               <gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>
            </p>
            <p n="4">4. The Jur<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> which found the said Office were <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s friends, and for mony vv<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> thing for his advantage, as <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> hath acknovvledged.</p>
            <p n="5">5. <hi>William Jenkinson</hi> one of the said Jury, that found the said Office then said unto him<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> that Mr. <hi>Copley</hi> had hard measure) that Mr. <hi>Copley</hi> knevv not vvhat to do vvith such an Est<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
               <hi>Nevile</hi> kept a good house, and vvould spend it among his Neighbours, and therefore did<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> it.</p>
            <p n="6">6. <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> then gave the Feodary <hi>Iohn Goodhand</hi> for his good service in finding <hi>Arthington</hi>-Hall, and at least 50. <hi>l. per Annum,</hi> for 2. <hi>s.</hi> yearly Rent, during Mr. <hi>Arth</hi>
               <gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ty (two years and an half.)</p>
            <p n="7">7. <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> saith that the said office vvas found, and sealed, and returned in du<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> and vvhether it vvas sealed according to the Statute, or that any omission of any part of<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> made, he cannot of his ovvn knovvledge depose.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Note,</hi> That this is an absolute perjury.</p>
            <p n="1">1. <hi>The Jury found</hi> Godfrey Copley <hi>to dye seised in Fee taile of all his lands, and found the D<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> of Intayle, and the Defendant</hi> Copley<hi>'s Wives Jointure Deed, and Writ, what they had found in six lines in the end of the said Office.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="2">2. <hi>The Escheator and Jury returned not the said Office under his hand and his and their Seals ingrossed in Parchment, according to the Statute, but gave it to</hi> Francis Nevile <hi>in tht Paper draught, who carried it to Counsell, and paid them their Fees, and altered it, and made</hi> G. Copley <hi>to dye seised in fee-simple of his</hi> Yorkshire <hi>lands, and left out the said Deed of Intaile, the said Jointure, Deed, and the said six lines writ in the end of the Office by the said Jury.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="3">3. Francis Nevile <hi>afterwards got it ingrossed in</hi> London, <hi>and he, and</hi> John Goodhand, <hi>and others forged the said Office and after their Tryalls to write like to the Escheators name, forged his name, and his and the Jurors seals to it, and then</hi> Francis Nevile <hi>filed it in the petty Bagg, as will appear by these following depositions.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>He saith that the next day after the finding of <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Office at <hi>Wakefield</hi> by the Jury,<note place="margin">
                  <hi>Barth. Roulst.</hi> A. 160. Int. 65</note>
               <hi>John Goodhand</hi> then Feodary, did in his presence and hearing read the said Office unto the said Jurors, as it was by them then found in Paper, and before it was engrossed, and therein read that it was found that the said <hi>G. Copley</hi> died seised <hi>in feodo talliato,</hi> and said unto the Jury, I perceive you have found the Deed of Intail, but afterwards when he this Deponent took a Copy of the said Office out of the Petty bag for the Defendant <hi>Copley,</hi> there was no mention of any Estate Tayle found therein, but only of an Estate in Fee simple, and the said Office was returned into the Petty bag, by the means of the Defendant <hi>Nevile.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>He doth not believe that <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Office was returned in the same words, that it was found,<note place="margin">
                  <hi>Rob. Benson</hi> C. 50. Int. 26.</note> for that he did see it at <hi>Lincolns Inn</hi> in Paper, and the Jurors hands unto the last Leaf, upon which Leaf there were some six or seven lines close written, which did mention a Deed to be found in the said Office, which Deed was left out in the return or ingrossement thereof.</p>
            <p>He saith that <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> did retain him as his Counsell to correct and peruse the said <hi>G.</hi>
               <note place="margin">
                  <hi>Rob. Lewis</hi> D. 42. Int. 35.</note>
               <hi>Copley</hi>'s Office, and he remembreth he had 20. <hi>s.</hi> Fee for the same, and its propable he might in form alter some<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing therein when he perused the paper Copy aforesaid.</p>
            <p>He saith that the Jury did intend,<note place="margin">
                  <hi>Char. Goodhand</hi> D. 13. Int. 4.</note> and mentioned to find in the said Office a Deed of Intail made be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween the said <hi>G. Copley</hi> on the one part, and <hi>Henry Sacheverell</hi> and <hi>Elizabeth</hi> his Wife on the other part and the Defendant <hi>Copley</hi>'s Wives Deed of Jointure was also mentioned to be found in the said Office, to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gether with Nine other Leases. And saith that the Jury caused all the perticulars that they would have found to be written in six Lines, at the end of the Paper Copy, which he hath seen, and all those parti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>culars are not mentioned in the Office returned into the Court.</p>
            <p>He saith that the said Office after the Death of <hi>G. Copley,</hi>
               <note place="margin">Int. 5.</note> was not returned truly as it was mentioned as aforesaid by the Jurors to be found, but saith that it was returned by the Jury in the Country only in Paper, not ingrossed in Parchment under the Escheators and Jurors hands and seals. And the said Paper Office was shewed unto Mr. <hi>Robert Lewis,</hi> Sergeant <hi>Boone,</hi> and Mr. <hi>Morgan,</hi> being of <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s Counsell, and some additions were made in the said Office for matter of form, and there were some dimi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nutions also, and things left out intended by the Jury to be found.</p>
            <p>He saith that the said Office was ingrossed afterwards at <hi>London,</hi> by Mr. <hi>Robert Lewis</hi> his Clerk,<note place="margin">Int. 6.</note> or some by his procurement, by the Direction of the Defendant Mr. <hi>Nevile,</hi> and was gratified by him.</p>
            <p>He saith that the Escheators name subscribed to the said Office is not of his own hand writing,<note place="margin">Int. 7.</note> but some other mans Writing, neither did the Escheator set his seal to the same, but the seal was set to it by another man, and the said Escheators name was writ, and a seal set to the said Office in the house of one <hi>Tho. Poulson</hi> a <hi>Goldsmith</hi> neer <hi>Temple Bar</hi> in <hi>London,</hi> in a Chamber where the said <hi>John Goodhand</hi> (the said Feodary) then lodged, and he doth not know that the said Office was sealed with the Escheators seal, or that it was done by any warrant or authority from the said Escheator, but by the appointment of the said <hi>Francis Ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vile</hi> and <hi>John Goodhand.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb n="18" facs="tcp:207188:23"/>
            <p>He <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>s present in the said Room when the said Escheators name was subscribed, and was <hi>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap>oodhand</hi>'s Clerk that attended him, and there were then also present the said <hi>John</hi>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> Defendant <hi>Francis Nevile,</hi> and he saith that the said <hi>John Goodhand, Francis Nevile,</hi>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>t, did every one of them make tryall how like they could write to the Escheators hand <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> Defendant <hi>Nevile</hi> did make tryall how like he could write to the Escheators name, before <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>ame was written to the said Office, which is returned, and he believeth that he that did <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> he Escheators hand writing, did set the Escheators name thereunto. And he saith that by <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>d perswasion, instance and direction of the said <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> and <hi>John Goodhand,</hi> the said <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>me was set to the said Office, and the said Office sealed.</p>
            <p>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>t the Escheator himself did not return the said Office, neither doth he know that he gave <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> other to return it, neither doth he know what reward or gratuity the Defenda<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>t <hi>Nevile</hi> gave <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> return it, but he saith that upon search made in the Office of the Petty bag it appeareth that <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>filed by the said <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> himself.</p>
            <p>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> Clerk in the Office of the Petty bag, received an Office found and returned after the death <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>f <hi>Sprotbrough</hi> in the County of <hi>Yorke</hi> Esquire, in or about the second day of <hi>May</hi> 10. <hi>Car.</hi>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>ut 8. <hi>April</hi> next before, and it was signed <hi>John Batt</hi> Es. which signified <hi>John Batt</hi> Es<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>ether <hi>John Batt</hi> writ his name, or set his seal himself to the said Office, or who did it, he <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> nor doth he know whether any Jurors names were subscribed, but referreth himself to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> But he believeth there were several seals when it was returned, being the seals of the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>d Jurors, by the Slits therein wherein the Labells were put. But by whom the said seals <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>noweth not, and it appeareth by the said Record that the Defendant <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> paid <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>ereof.</p>
            <p>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>, Will he that dare thus perjure himself, and forge an Office, scruple at the forging of a Lease for his to great advantage?</p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>d <hi>Bramstons</hi>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>tificate 30 <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>. 15. <hi>Car. Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                     <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </hi> 1639.</note>
               <hi>Note,</hi> The Lord chief Justice <hi>Bramston</hi> upon a Reference to him, struck out the 5. and 8. Interr. to <hi>Charles Goodhand</hi> as scandalous to Mr. <hi>Nevile,</hi> which proved the falsifying of the Office, and the for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ging of the hand and seals of the said Escheator and Jurors, so that they ware thereby prevented from be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing read at the hearing in the <hi>Star Chamber.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>This is the Petitioners first grievance for which they appeal to the Parliament.</p>
         </div>
         <div n="3" type="chapter">
            <head>
               <hi>CHAP. III.</hi> That then the Defendant <hi>Nevile,</hi> coulerably grounded a Suit in the Court of Wards against the Defendants <hi>William Copley,</hi> and <hi>Edmund Hastings,</hi> and <hi>Mary</hi> his Wife, and having then &amp; there produced the Defen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dant <hi>William Hawet</hi> and other perjured Witnesses, and upon a preagreement, combination, and collusion with the said <hi>Copley</hi> and <hi>Hastings,</hi> they knowing the said Lease to be forged, and by other unlawful means obtained a Decree in that Court, wherein your Petitioner <hi>Mary</hi> was no Party (though principally concerned) for allowance and further countenancing of the said forged Lease.</head>
            <div n="1" type="section">
               <head>
                  <hi>Sect.</hi> 1.</head>
               <p n="1">1. <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s Decree was obtained by the Perjury of the Defendant <hi>William Hawet,</hi> and by the perjury or delusion of <hi>Hugh Everard.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="1">1. By the Perjury of <hi>William Hawet.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>ill. Hawet <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>urt of Wards</hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>. Def. <hi>Nevil <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap> Hastings.</hi> fol. <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> Int. 18. <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>illiam Hawet</hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ledgex m. fol. 41. <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>t. 1. <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>d.</hi> 21. <hi>Nov.</hi> 4. <hi>Car.</hi> 9. <hi>No.</hi> 14. <hi>Car.</hi> 8. <hi>Iun.</hi> 15. <hi>Car.</hi> 0. <hi>No.</hi> 15. <hi>Car.</hi>
                  </note>
                  <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s Lease was sealed and delivered by <hi>G. Copley</hi> at <hi>Sprotbrough</hi> about 1. <hi>Novemb.</hi> 1632. <hi>Hugh Everard, John Swinden,</hi> and others were present with him the said <hi>Hawet</hi> at the sealing and deli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very of it. <hi>Contrar.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>He doth not know that <hi>G. Copley</hi> sealed and delivered <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s Lease, neither was he present, not doth he know who was present at the sealing and delivery of it, or when, or where it was sealed or delivered.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Note,</hi> The Court of <hi>Star Chamber</hi> would not upon the Petitioners several motions grant them leave to use at the hearing there, the Defendant <hi>Hawet</hi>'s Deposition in the Coutt of Wards, but referred it to the two Lord chief Justices <hi>Bramston</hi> and <hi>Finch,</hi> to report what they thought fit to do therein, who in almost a years soliciting with great pains and charge would never meet about it, and yet at the hearing granted Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi> the use of <hi>Thomas Walker</hi>'s Depositions in the Court of Requests, who had deposed against the said Lease in the <hi>Star Chamber.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This is the Petitioners second grievance, for which they appeal to the Parliament.</p>
               <p n="2">2. By the perjury or delusion of <hi>Hugh Everard.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <hi>Hugh Everard <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>ourt of Wards <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>ran. Nevile</hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>laintiff and <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>dm. Hastings</hi> Def. f. 7. Int. 17 <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ugh Everard</hi> Court of Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                     <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>uests. int. <hi>Ellen Nevile</hi> Quer. and <hi>Fran. Nevile</hi> Def. <hi>ex parte</hi> Quer. fol. 1. Int 20. &amp; f. 77. Int. 20. <hi>Will. Copley Court of Wards</hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>l. 17. Int. 28.</note>
                  <hi>G. Copley</hi> about <hi>Nov.</hi> was two years, <hi>viz.</hi> 1632. sealed several Writings, but what they were he knew not, nor to whom they were delivered, but to <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s use he is fully assured.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Contrar.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>He now remembers not how many Leases he set his hand unto, when they were sealed by <hi>G. Copley,</hi> nor doth he know for whose use they were so sealed and executed, further then that <hi>G. Copley</hi> then declared himself that they were for the use of his Cousin <hi>Nevile.</hi> The Interrogatory is, Whether were the said Leases delivered for the Plaintiff <hi>Ellen Nevile,</hi> or the Defendant <hi>Francis Nevile.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Note,</hi> In the former deposition <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap>re delivered to the use of <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> he is fully assured. In the latter they were delivered for <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> of his Cousin <hi>Nevile,</hi> but whether for the use of <hi>Ellen Nevile</hi> or <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> he doth not know. Is not this a Perjury?</p>
            </div>
            <div n="2" type="section">
               <head>
                  <hi>Sect. 2.</hi> The Decree was obtained by the Agreement, Combination and Collusion of the Defendants <hi>Francis Nevile,</hi> and <hi>William Copley.</hi>
               </head>
               <p n="1">1. <hi>William Copley</hi> verily believeth that the said <hi>G. Copley</hi> deceased would not have done any Act at any time, which should have been unjust, or which he had no power to do.</p>
               <p n="2">2. <hi>William Copley</hi> knew that <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> had nothing to shew for any thing left him by <hi>G. Copley,</hi> and
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:207188:24"/> that <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> sued him and <hi>Edmund Hastings,</hi>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <hi>Will. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ec<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </hi> A. 109. I<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> 101. <hi>James Pie<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </hi> A. 120. In<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> 102. <hi>John Roger.</hi> A. 89. Int. 1 <hi>Hercy Nevi<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </hi> A. 91. Int. 1</note> only to work mischief amongst them (and although <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> had said that if the Divel made his Lease, and his Dam had sealed it, he would make it serve his turn) that there was a world of Knavery in it.</p>
               <p n="3">3. <hi>William Copley</hi> knew that <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s Leases were forged, and made, and sealed at <hi>Cheet-hall Francis Nevile</hi>'s house by the Defendant <hi>Clayton,</hi> commonly called by a By name of <hi>Badsticks.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="4">4. <hi>William Copley</hi> did not examine <hi>Thomas Walker</hi> and <hi>Richard Elton,</hi> two of <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s Wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nesses, to his pretended Leases, and who have now denied their names to be of their own hand writing, and <hi>Godfrey Copley</hi>'s sealing and delivering of it.</p>
               <p n="5">5. <hi>William Copley</hi> knew that <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> had destroyed his Leases <hi>(quantum ad illum)</hi> if rightly obtained by the said Award, that he had made betwixt him and <hi>Edmund Hastings.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="6">6. <hi>William Copley</hi> agreed with <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> a good while before the Decree, and bought of him 3. Leases for 3200 <hi>l.</hi> for which he demanded of <hi>William Copley</hi> 10000 <hi>l.</hi>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <hi>D<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>rcy Washi<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ton.</hi> B. 55. In<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                     <hi>Ralph <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>indo<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </hi> E. 49. Int. 83 <hi>Emman. Mo<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </hi> D. 69. Int.<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                     <hi>J. Whittake<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </hi> E. 51. Int.<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                     <hi>Tho. Radley</hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap> E. 5. Int. 8 <hi>Anth. Hatfie<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </hi> E. 28. Int. 8 <hi>Rob. Crumwe<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </hi> E. 41. Int. 82 <hi>Godfrey Copl<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </hi> A. 66. Int. 5 <hi>Bart. Roulsto</hi> A. 106. Int. 9 Int. 71. <hi>supr. Gervas Nevi<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </hi> K. 26. Int. 33 <hi>Tho. Proctor</hi> H. 17. Int. 2 <hi>Tho. Hobson</hi> 89. Int. 7. <hi>su<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </hi> Decree <hi>Cou<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap> of Wards</hi> 9. <hi>May</hi> 11. <hi>Car. Edm. Hasting</hi> Ex. 53. Int. 2 Int. 3. <hi>Leon. Pinckn<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </hi> B. 49. Int. 2 <hi>Tho. Walker</hi> B. 75. Int.<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                     <hi>Bart. Rowtsto.</hi> A. 160. Int. 7 <hi>supra. Tho. Walker</hi> B. 75. Int. 9. Commission <hi>int.</hi> Mr. <hi>Nev<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </hi> &amp; <hi>Hastings</hi> e<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                     <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ecuted at <hi>Barnsley</hi> 10 <hi>A</hi> 11. <hi>Car. Court of Wards.</hi> Decree of 11. <hi>Court of War<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </hi> 9 <hi>May.</hi> 11 <hi>Ca<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap> Fran. Nevile</hi>'<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> Ex. 18. Int. 21 <hi>Fran. Nevile</hi>'<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> Answer to <hi>Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pley</hi>'s Bill in the Court of Wards fol. 2<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                     <hi>Edm. Hastings</hi> Ex. 53. Int. 2. <hi>John Goodhan<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </hi> E. 22. Int. 20. <hi>Leon. Pinckn y</hi> B. 49. Int. 1. <hi>Edm. Hastings</hi> Affadavit in <hi>Cam. Stellat.</hi> 28. <hi>Nov.</hi> 14. <hi>Car. Edm. Hastings</hi> Ex. 53. Int. 21. <hi>Emman. Mote</hi> D. 69. Int. 2.</note> and which were worth 20000 <hi>l</hi> had they not been forged. <hi>viz.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="1">1. <hi>His Lease of the Demeasnes of</hi> Sprotbrough <hi>and</hi> Newton <hi>for</hi> 21. <hi>years worth</hi> 460. <hi>l. per Annum, and of Woods which he might cut down and sell worth</hi> 9000 <hi>l.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="2">2. <hi>His Lease of</hi> G. Copley<hi>'s purchased Lands for</hi> 80. <hi>years worth</hi> 160. <hi>l. per Annum.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="3">3. <hi>His Lease of</hi> Plumtree, <hi>and</hi> G. Copley<hi>'s other</hi> Nottinghamshire <hi>lands for</hi> 80. <hi>years determinable upon three lives, viz.</hi> Francis Nevile<hi>'s, his Brother</hi> Gervas Nevile<hi>'s, and his Son</hi> Sandford Nevile<hi>'s worth about</hi> 800 <hi>l. per Annum.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>William Copley</hi> a good while before the said Decree, bought all these of <hi>Francis Nevile,</hi> excepting the Demeasnes of <hi>Plumtree</hi> for 3200 <hi>l.</hi> The Demeasnes of <hi>Plumtree</hi> are worth 180 <hi>l. per Annum.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Note</hi> 1. <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s evasion of this sale, because it speaks his Lease to be forged, and how he is catcheth it.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> told his Brother <hi>Gervas</hi> that the want of <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Deed of power, because Mr. <hi>Bower</hi> had given the Keys to <hi>William Copley,</hi> enforced him to take so low a composition and produceth him to depose it. <hi>Contrar.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Mr. <hi>Proctor</hi> advised <hi>Gervas Nevile</hi> to search the Rowles and the <hi>Exchequer,</hi> for <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Deed of power, and <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> after <hi>Hillary</hi> Term 1633. left his three Leases and <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Deed of power with him to draw up <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Office, which was before the Suit was commenced in the Court of Wards, and above a year before the Decree was there obtained, for the Office was found 8. <hi>April</hi> 10. <hi>Car.</hi> and the Decree made 9. <hi>May</hi> 11. <hi>Car.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Note</hi> 2. The Lands in the Petitioners Leases as appears by Mr. <hi>Hatfield</hi> and Mr. <hi>Crumwell,</hi> were worth about 800 <hi>l. per Annum, Francis Nevile</hi> sold all these to the Defendant <hi>Copley</hi> except the Demeasnes of <hi>Plumtree,</hi> worth 180 <hi>l. per Annum,</hi> as <hi>Barth. Rowlston</hi> hath deposed, so that <hi>William Copley</hi> purchasing 600. <hi>l. per Annum</hi> of the Petitioners Leases, for 99. years determinable upon three lives, got about 3000 <hi>l.</hi> out of the Petitioners Estate, more then he paid to <hi>Francis Nevile,</hi> for all his said three Leases.</p>
               <p>This caused the Defendant <hi>Copley</hi> to agree and combine with <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> against the Petitioner and her Leases.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="3" type="section">
               <head>
                  <hi>Sect. 3.</hi> The Decree was obtained by the Combination, Agreement, and Collusion of the Defendants <hi>Fran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cis Nevile</hi> and <hi>Edmund Hastings.</hi>
               </head>
               <p n="1">1. <hi>Edmund Hastings</hi> knew <hi>G. Copley</hi> to be a just dealing man and peaceable.</p>
               <p n="2">2. He knows not how to believe concerning <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s making of <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s Lease.</p>
               <p n="3">3. <hi>Edmund Hastings</hi> knew <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s said Lease to be forged, and asked him with what Consci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ence he could swear that <hi>G. Copley</hi> made it; <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> answered him, that if a man could get such an Estate as that was with swearing, who is it, that would not swear everlastingly.</p>
               <p n="4">4. <hi>Edmund Hastings</hi> did not then examine <hi>Thomas Walker</hi> and <hi>Richard Elton</hi> two of the witnesses to his pretended Lease, although they were then his houshold Servants, and have now denyed their writing of their names to it, and <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s sealing and delivering of it.</p>
               <p n="5">5. <hi>Edmund Hastings</hi> knew that <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> by making the said Award between him and <hi>William Copley,</hi> and giving <hi>William Copley</hi> by it 1400 <hi>l.</hi> or his Estate for a Lease of the Demeasnes of <hi>Plumtree</hi> for 21. years, had destroyed his own Lease <hi>(quantum ad illum)</hi> if it had been rightly obtained.</p>
               <p n="6">6. <hi>Edmund Hastings</hi> writ from <hi>Newark</hi> to his Counsell at <hi>London,</hi> to stay proceedings till be came up for that <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> and he were upon terms of Agreement.</p>
               <p n="7">7. <hi>Edmund Hastings</hi> being in possession of the Demeasnes of <hi>Plumtree,</hi> came to an hearing with <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> the said term, that a Commission for examining of Witnesses betwixt them was returned; whereas he might have prayed another Commission for examining <hi>Thomas Walker,</hi> and <hi>Richard Elton,</hi> two of the witnesses to <hi>Francis Neviles</hi> pretended Lease, and then kept the possession 12. Months longer, The Dates of the Commission and Decree proves that.</p>
               <p n="8">8. <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> confesseth his agreement with <hi>Edmund Hastings</hi> before the Decree, and that if he recovered the premisses, that <hi>Edmund Hastings</hi> should have a convenient time therein or purchase it at a reasonable rate, but it was not put into Articles or Covenants in Writing.</p>
               <div type="part">
                  <head>
                     <hi>Francis Neviles</hi> Perujry in the lust Deposition.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Note</hi> 1. He deposed in the Court of Wards, that there was no Speech or Treaty of any end to be made betwixt him and <hi>Edmund Hastings</hi> till first there should be a hearing.</p>
                  <p n="2">2. The said Agreement betwixt <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> and <hi>Edmund Hastings,</hi> before the Decree was put into Articles in Writing, and upon <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s Assignment of the Demeasnes of <hi>Plumtree,</hi> for Mr. <hi>Hastings</hi> use, or shortly after the said Articles of Agreement were cancelled and torn in pieces.</p>
                  <p n="9">9. <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> assigned to <hi>Edmund Hastings</hi> the Demeasnes of <hi>Plumtree</hi> 16. <hi>Jun.</hi> 10. <hi>Car.</hi> for 2650 <hi>l.</hi> but there were only paid 850 <hi>l.</hi> and <hi>Edmund Hastings</hi> assigned the Remainder to be paid to <hi>Fran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cis
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:207188:25"/> Nevile</hi> by the Defendant <hi>Copley,</hi> who never owed <hi>Edmund Hastings</hi> above 10 <hi>l.</hi> or thereabouts, it was only a pretence to colour theit combination.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Note, Edmund Hastings</hi> having a conditional Moyety of the Petitioners Leases, <hi>viz.</hi> in case he and his Wife setled <hi>Bentley</hi> upon the Petitioner <hi>Mary,</hi> and her heirs within a year after the death of the said <hi>G. Copley,</hi> and not having performed it, but contrary to vowes and protestations sold it away from her to Sir <hi>John Bale</hi> and Mr. <hi>Iobson,</hi> combined with <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> to get a decree for his Lease, and then to pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chase it at an under value, and <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> for this cause left the Petitioner out of his Bill, although she was principally, indeed wholly concerned in it.</p>
                  <p>The Petitioner was thus defrauded both of <hi>Bentley</hi> and her Leases.</p>
               </div>
            </div>
         </div>
         <div n="4" type="chapter">
            <head>
               <hi>CHAP. IV. Francis Nevile</hi>'s further tampering, suborning, bribing, and attempting to bribe witnesses both by himself and others.</head>
            <div n="1" type="section">
               <head>
                  <hi>1. Francis Nevile</hi> and his Servant the Defendant <hi>Hawet</hi> endevoured to get <hi>Thomas Walker</hi> out of Mr. <hi>Hastings</hi> Service, and to serve him.</head>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap>. <hi>Walker</hi> 15. Int. 12.</note>Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi> about 3. years since told <hi>Thomas Walker</hi> that he had heard that he had left Mr. <hi>Hastings,</hi> and that he thought to have sent for him to serve him, The Defendant <hi>Hawet</hi> about a year after told him that he got nothing in Mr. <hi>Hastings</hi> Service, but if he would serve Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi> he should be maintained well, and if he refused, Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi> would help him to a Keepers place in <hi>Brierly</hi> Park, worth 20. or 30. <hi>l. per Annum. Hawet</hi> at another time told him, that if he would come to Mr. <hi>Nevile,</hi> he would perform his promise. But he told them both that whilst they had Suits he would not leave his old Master, and he believeth that their intents were to have prevailed with him to have sworn that he saw his Lease sea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led and delivered by <hi>G. Copley</hi> as his Act and Deed.</p>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <hi>Joh. Waidson</hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>0. Int. 5.</note>Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi> spake to him when he last saw his Lease, to wish <hi>Thomas Walker</hi> to be his Servant, and to promise him any reasonable conditions. But considering with himself by the increase of witnesses that Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi> might have some ill end in it, he never medled with <hi>Walker.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="2" type="section">
               <head>
                  <hi>2. Francis Nevile</hi>'s tampering with <hi>Richard Elton.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>n. Hastings</hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>. 53. Int. 9. <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                           <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                        </gap>. Heyward</hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> 123. Int. 4, <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>9. <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>h. Copley</hi> D. 1. Int. 6, 7, <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>, 19. <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>h. Elton</hi> 7. Int. 25.</note>
                  <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> laboured to get him out of Mr. <hi>Hastings</hi> service, and to serve him or his Mother. He examined him not at the Commission, when he was examined on the Petitioners part, and when he himself examined his other witnesses <hi>Everard</hi> and <hi>Swinden;</hi> But brought him to <hi>London,</hi> and then carried him to his Chamber, and there tampered with him, telling him that he had not troubled him, but that he heard he had denied his name to his Lease to be of his own hand writing, which he hoped he would not do, and shewed him his said Lease, and said that he was but a bad Scribe, and might easily be mistaken in the knowing of his name, and then shewed him a Paper, wherein was written <hi>Elon</hi> instead of <hi>Elton,</hi> and another paper wherein he had written <hi>Elton</hi> like to his name upon the said Lease, and then <hi>Elton</hi> told him that he knew not that he had written either of those names, nor could he absolutely swear that his name to his Lease was of his own hand writing, And <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> then told him again that it was true he could not, and said he was a vile wicked man, that would swear for his own hand to any writing, that he had not in his custody.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="3" type="section">
               <head>
                  <hi>3. Francis Nevile</hi> after his tampering with <hi>Walker</hi> and <hi>Elton,</hi> supposing it not sufficient, suborned two Common Bailiffs <hi>John Holdsworth</hi> and <hi>Robert Siddall,</hi> and <hi>William Farburne</hi> a Taylor, falsly to testi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fie that five witnesses, two of which were <hi>Thomas Walker</hi> and <hi>Richard Elton</hi> did depose for his said Leases at <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Office finding at <hi>Wakefield.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                     <hi>Holdsworth</hi> 39. Int. 5. <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>b. Siddall</hi> 48. Int. 3.</note>Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi> produced at <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Office finding at <hi>Wakefield</hi> to prove his three Leases, <hi>Hugh Everard, John Swinden, Robert Soreby, Thomas Walk r,</hi> and <hi>Richard Elton.</hi> And they all deposed that the said Leases were sealed and delivered by <hi>G. Copley</hi> as his Act and Deed. And that they were witnesses thereunto.</p>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                     <hi>Farbu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ne</hi> 55. Int. 3.</note>Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi> proved his three Leases at <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Office finding at <hi>Wakefield,</hi> to be sealed and executed by <hi>G. Copley</hi> by five several Witnesses, two of which were of his Acquaintance, and their names were <hi>Thomas Walker</hi> and <hi>Richard Elton,</hi> but the names of the other three he remembers not.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Contrar.</hi>
               </p>
               <div n="1" type="part">
                  <head>
                     <hi>1.</hi> But three witnesses were then and there sworn for the said Lease.</head>
                  <p>
                     <note place="margin">
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                           <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                        </gap>. <hi>Geo. Went<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>orth</hi> 1. 14. <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>t. 2, 3. <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <hi>Edw. Roads</hi> 19. Int. 2, 3. <hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>pra. <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>hn Goodhand</hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap> 22. Int. 12. <hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>ho. Walker G.</hi> 1 Int. 3. <hi>ex <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>arte Francis <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>evile. <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>ho Walker</hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>. 75. Int. 7. <hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>c. Elton</hi> G. 45 <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>nt. 2 9. <hi>ex par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                           <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>e Franc. Nevile</hi>
                     </note>Sir <hi>George Wentworth,</hi> and Sir <hi>Edward Roads,</hi> on Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi>'s part have deposed but for three Witnesses <hi>Everard, Swinden,</hi> and <hi>Soreby,</hi> to be sworn for Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi>'s Leases, at <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Office finding at <hi>Wake<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>field.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>The Feodary <hi>John Goodhand</hi> saith, that three Witnesses were sworn at <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Office finding; to prove the sealing and delivery of Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi>'s Lease.</p>
               </div>
               <div n="2" type="part">
                  <head>
                     <hi>2. Thomas Walker</hi> was not then at <hi>Wakefield,</hi> but was at <hi>Sprotbrough</hi> about <hi>14</hi> miles distant from it.</head>
                  <p>Richard Elton <hi>was then there, but</hi> Francis Nevile <hi>did not produce him as a witnesse.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Thomas Walker</hi> was Mr. <hi>Hastings</hi> servant, when <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Office was found at <hi>Wakefield</hi> but he was not then at <hi>Wakefield.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Thomas Walker</hi> hath not formerly deposed for Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi>'s Lease, neither at <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Office find<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing at <hi>Wakefield,</hi> nor in the Court of Wards, nor ever before now was summoned, to depose for his hand writing to be thereunto endorsed.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Richard Elton</hi> was at <hi>Wakefield,</hi> but vvas not in Court at the finding of <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Office, he desired Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi> to spare him, and he told him he vvould spare him, and he being then left in the Tovvn vvas not then called to vvitnesse any thing, and he thought himself much beholden to Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi> that he spa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red him.</p>
                  <p>
                     <note place="margin">
                        <hi>Emm<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>n. Mote.</hi> D 69. Int. 5.</note>He vvas at <hi>Wakefield</hi> at <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Office finding, and savv <hi>Everard, Swinden,</hi> and another svvorn, but <hi>Thomas Walker</hi> vvas not there, nor was svvorn for Mr. <hi>Nevile,</hi> vvhich he knovvs to be true, because
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:207188:26"/> he hearing the said <hi>Walker</hi>'s name used as a witnesse to the said Lease, asked the Defendant <hi>Hastings</hi> (whose Servant he was) why he brought him not thither? and he replied, he knew not that any use would be of him there, and that he had left him at home to wait upon his Wife.</p>
                  <p>He attended upon his Master <hi>Copley</hi> at <hi>Wakefield</hi> when <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Office was found,<note place="margin">
                        <hi>Rich. Bal<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>
                        </hi> D. 104. I<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </note> and he well re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>members that <hi>Thomas Walker</hi> was left at home, and was not produced or sworn touching the matters in question at that time.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Richard Elton</hi> was then at <hi>Wakefield</hi> but was not sworn,<note place="margin">Int. 4.</note>
                     <hi>Elton</hi> told him rhat he had made means to be spared, for that he said he could do Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi> no good.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Thomas Walker</hi> was not at <hi>Wakefield</hi> at <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Office finding,<note place="margin">
                        <hi>Will. Nes<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>
                        </hi> E. 15. Int.<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                           <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </note> but was in <hi>Sprotbrough</hi> in his compa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny, and he the better knows it to be true, for that he was booted and spurr'd to have gone to <hi>Wakefield</hi> that day with Mr. <hi>Copley,</hi> but was afterwards countermanded, and stayed at home with the said <hi>Walker.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>She was not at <hi>Wakefield</hi> when <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Office was found, but saith that upon that day,<note place="margin">
                        <hi>Mary Butte</hi> E. 42. Int.<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                           <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </note> the Defen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dants <hi>Copley</hi> and <hi>Hastings,</hi> said that they went to <hi>Wakefield</hi> to find it, <hi>Thomas Walker</hi> was at <hi>Sprotbrough</hi> all that day and not at <hi>Wakefield,</hi> which she knows to be true, for that she then was Servant to Mr. <hi>Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pley</hi> of <hi>Sprotbrough,</hi> where <hi>Thomas VValker</hi> then lived.</p>
                  <p>He was the Defendant <hi>Copley</hi>'s Servant, and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ttended on him to <hi>VVakefield</hi> at <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Office find<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing,<note place="margin">
                        <hi>Tho. Baldo<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>
                        </hi> D. 120. Int.<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                           <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </note> and doth well remember that <hi>Thomas VValker</hi> was not produced as a witnesse there, neither doth he believe that he was at <hi>VVakefield</hi> that day, and is the more confirmed in his opinion and belief, because <hi>VVilliam Neschall</hi> and <hi>Mary Buttery</hi> his Fellow Servants, and living in houshold with <hi>Thomas VValker,</hi> did tell him at his coming from <hi>VVakefield,</hi> that <hi>Thomas VValker</hi> and they had been very merry, and had played a Match at Tutts, or at the Ball.</p>
                  <p>He believeth that <hi>Thomas VValker</hi> was not at <hi>VVakefield</hi> at <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Office finding,<note place="margin">
                        <hi>Tho. West</hi> B. Int. 5. 9. <hi>Will. Bo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="3 letters">
                              <desc>•••</desc>
                           </gap>
                        </hi>
                     </note> both because he saw him not there, and for that the Defendant <hi>Hastings</hi> told him that he had left him at home to attend his Mistresse.</p>
                  <p>He believes that <hi>Richard Elton</hi> was there, but not sworn,<note place="margin">
                        <hi>Rob. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="3 letters">
                              <desc>•••</desc>
                           </gap>ywa<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>
                        </hi> D. 123. In<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap> 14. <hi>R. Crum<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                              <desc>•…</desc>
                           </gap>
                        </hi> E. 41. Int. 1 <hi>Order</hi> 11.<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                           <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                        </gap> 15. <hi>Car.</hi>
                     </note> for Mr. <hi>Hastings</hi> told him that <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> refused to have him sworn, saying he would spare him, for he thought the other witnesses were sufficient.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Note,</hi> The Court of <hi>Star Chamber</hi> by their Order of that Term (when this cause was to be heard) that but two Witnesses should be read to a point) prevented the manifestation of the Perjuries of <hi>Holds<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>worth, Syddall,</hi> and <hi>Farburne,</hi> and made two of their Depositions as good as the Petitioners Twelve. This Order was never entred.</p>
                  <p>This is the Petitioners third grievance and cause of Appeal.</p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div n="4" type="section">
               <head>
                  <hi>4. Francis Nevile</hi> suborned his Butler <hi>John Pollard,</hi> falsly to depose a Negative, that Sir <hi>John Waid<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>son</hi> was not at his house at <hi>Cheet</hi> before <hi>Christmas</hi> next after <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s death <hi>1633.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>He knows Sir <hi>John VVaidson</hi> Knight, and he was not at Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi>'s house from that day Mr.<note place="margin">
                     <hi>Iohn Pollar<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </hi> l. 118. Int.<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </note>
                  <hi>Nevile</hi> came from <hi>London</hi> after <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Death, about a fornight before <hi>Christmas</hi> until <hi>Christmas</hi> day was past, being <hi>Christmas</hi> 1633.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Contrar.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi> shewed him his said Lease at <hi>Cheet,</hi> about 14, 15, or 16. of <hi>Decemb.</hi> next after <hi>G.</hi>
                  <note place="margin">Sr. <hi>Ioh. Waid<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </hi> B. 20. Int. 1. <hi>Francis Ju<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </hi> B. 33. Int. 2 4.</note>
                  <hi>Copley</hi>'s Death, and between St. <hi>Stephens</hi> day, and <hi>New years</hi> day following, he shewed it him again at <hi>Cheet.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Sir <hi>John VVaidson</hi> Knight, about 10. or 11. <hi>December</hi> next after <hi>G. Copley</hi>'s Death, met <hi>Francis Ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vile</hi> at <hi>Sprotbrough.</hi> About 14, 15, or 16. of the said Month, the said Sir <hi>John VVaidson</hi> went to Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi>'s house at <hi>Cheet,</hi> and this he knows, for that he was then and there present as a Sevant attending upon Sir <hi>John VVaidson;</hi> and he, and the said Sir <hi>John</hi> about St. <hi>Stephens day,</hi> or St. <hi>Johns day</hi> following, in the same Month, went again to the said Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi>'s house at <hi>Cheet.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> confessed to Mr. <hi>Conyers,</hi> that he shewed his said Lease to Sir <hi>John VVaidson</hi> at <hi>Cheet,</hi>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <hi>Robert Cony<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </hi> B. 38. Int. 2</note> about three Weeks before <hi>Christmas</hi> 1633. And that about St. <hi>Stephens</hi> day following, he the said Sir <hi>John</hi> coming thither again about reconciling him and Mr. <hi>Copley,</hi> he again shewed it unto him there.</p>
               <p>Mr. <hi>Nevile</hi> Interrogates Sir <hi>John VVaidson</hi> if the Parsonages of <hi>Sprotbrough</hi> and of <hi>Plumtree,</hi>
                  <note place="margin">Sr. <hi>Ioh. Waid<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </hi> G. 16. Int. 9</note> were not the two Writings he at first time shewed him at <hi>Cheet,</hi> being witnessed only with two Witnesses. The words (first time) imply that he was there before <hi>Christmas.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Interrogate if <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> would not have given him a 100 <hi>l.</hi>
                  <note place="margin">Inter. this.</note> to have deposed that he had seen his said Lease so witnessed as now it is, before <hi>Christmas</hi> 1633. and before the time that Sir <hi>John VVaidson</hi> hath deposed that he saw it only with two Witnesses to it.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Note,</hi> Will he that dare suborn four witnesses, and attempt to suborn a fifth to perjure themselves in swearing against the Petitioners Witnesses who had deposed against his said Lease, want Witnesses to svvear for the Lease it self?</p>
            </div>
         </div>
         <div n="5" type="chapter">
            <head>
               <hi>CHAP. V. Francis Nevile</hi>'s corrupting <hi>James Gerrard</hi> and <hi>Edvvard Coulson</hi> two of the Examiners in the <hi>Star-Chamber.</hi>
            </head>
            <p n="1">1. To examine some of the Petitioners Witnesses unequally, and to falsify some of their Depositions.<note place="margin">The Petitio<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ne<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>s Affada 29. <hi>No.</hi> 14. <hi>Ca.</hi>
               </note>
            </p>
            <p n="2">2. To endorse and disendorse Witnesses names upon <hi>Francis Nevile</hi>'s Lease as examined.</p>
            <p n="3">3. To deliver some Depositions of the Petitioners Witnesses to <hi>Francis Nevile</hi> before publication.</p>
            <p n="4">4. To deliver to the said <hi>Francis Nevile,</hi> his said Lease out of Court without order to tamper with Witnesses before he examined them.</p>
            <div n="1" type="section">
               <head>
                  <hi>Sect. 1.</hi> The Examiners did examine some of the Petitioners witnesses unequally and falsified some of their depositions.</head>
               <p n="1">1. <hi>James Gerrard</hi> pressed Mr. <hi>VVest</hi> to depose certainly and punctually to what was not in his know<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge or remembrance.</p>
               <gap reason="missing" extent="1+ pages">
                  <desc>〈1+ pages missing〉</desc>
               </gap>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>